<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage</title>
    <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/</link>
    <description>Homepage</description>
    <copyright>Copyright Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 22:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.wmar2news.com/index.rss" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" />
    <item>
      <title>Gorgeous weather to get outside today</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/weather/weather-blogs/gorgeous-weather-to-get-outside-today</link>
      <description>The wind won't be quite as strong today, which will make it an ideal day to grill outside. Winds will gust to around 20 mph</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Abigail Degler</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/weather/weather-blogs/gorgeous-weather-to-get-outside-today</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/weather/weather-blogs/gorgeous-weather-to-get-outside-today">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Today will be one of the nicest days we've seen in a while, as temperatures finally climb into the lower to middle 70s. We dealt with strong gusty winds the last few days, but the wind should be calmer today. We still expect occasional gusts over 20 mph, especially in the afternoon hours. The weather will be perfect this afternoon to get out and take a walk, catch up on yardwork, or do any grilling. If you do plan on grilling, just keep in mind the wind may still blow things around quite a bit. The wind that we saw this weekend has led to elevated tree pollen, so if you are an allergy sufferer, be mindful of that if you plan to be outside. </p><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/9e/45/ff393f87411589e2bab78eab6e6b/wxxx.jpg"></figure>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rowhomes damaged after vacant house fire in West Baltimore</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/rowhomes-damaged-after-vacant-house-fire-in-west-baltimore</link>
      <description>Baltimore firefighters were on the scene of a vacant house fire in West Baltimore, Saturday afternoon.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 21:10:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Rushaad Hayward</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/rowhomes-damaged-after-vacant-house-fire-in-west-baltimore</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/rowhomes-damaged-after-vacant-house-fire-in-west-baltimore">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Baltimore firefighters were on the scene of a vacant house fire in West Baltimore, Saturday afternoon.</p><p>The fire took place in the 2500 block of Woodbrook Avenue and was upgraded to two alarms. </p><p>Officials say no one was injured but the surrounding rowhomes were damaged. </p><p>There's no word on the cause of this fire at this time. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man arrested for allegedly shooting in the air near race track during Preakness</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/man-arrested-for-allegedly-shooting-in-the-air-near-race-track-during-preakness</link>
      <description>A man has been arrested for allegedly shooting a gun in the air near the Pimlico Race Track during Preakness.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 19:29:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Rushaad Hayward</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/man-arrested-for-allegedly-shooting-in-the-air-near-race-track-during-preakness</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/man-arrested-for-allegedly-shooting-in-the-air-near-race-track-during-preakness">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>A man has been arrested for allegedly shooting a gun in the air near the Pimlico Race Track during Preakness. </p><p>Around 6:45 p.m., officers in their patrol car heard shots fired in the 5600 block of Key Avenue. </p><p>After speaking to witnesses in the area, they learned a man wearing a red shirt and carrying a YETI cup allegedly fired the gun.</p><p>Police found the man, later identified as Bernard Cunningham, and placed him under arrest after he initially tried to avoid officers. </p><p>Prior to the arrest, a handgun was recovered from his waistband.</p><p>Investigation revealed he had a handgun permit and later determined it was valid. </p><p>Police say detectives then reviewed surveillance video that showed Cunningham sitting on the steps of a house on Key Avenue, pulling out a gun and shooting 10 rounds into the air.</p><p>"It should be noted the concern for public safety due to the discharging which transpired approximately 100 yards to the Pimlico Race Track on the day of Preakness," police records say.</p><p>The records also note the several thousand people in attendance for the race. </p><p>Detectives say Cunningham "displayed several behavioral indicators consistent with being under the influence." This included slurred speech, glassy eyes and an alcohol smell coming from his breath. </p><p>Alcohol residue was found in Cunnigham's YETI cup as well. </p><p>Cunningham was later taken to Central Booking for processing. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
