<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Local News</title>
    <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local</link>
    <description>Local News</description>
    <copyright>Copyright Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 21:10:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local.rss" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" />
    <item>
      <title>Rowhomes damaged after vacant house fire in West Baltimore</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/rowhomes-damaged-after-vacant-house-fire-in-west-baltimore</link>
      <description>Baltimore firefighters were on the scene of a vacant house fire in West Baltimore, Saturday afternoon.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 21:10:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Rushaad Hayward</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/rowhomes-damaged-after-vacant-house-fire-in-west-baltimore</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/rowhomes-damaged-after-vacant-house-fire-in-west-baltimore">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Baltimore firefighters were on the scene of a vacant house fire in West Baltimore, Saturday afternoon.</p><p>The fire took place in the 2500 block of Woodbrook Avenue and was upgraded to two alarms. </p><p>Officials say no one was injured but the surrounding rowhomes were damaged. </p><p>There's no word on the cause of this fire at this time. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man arrested for allegedly shooting in the air near race track during Preakness</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/man-arrested-for-allegedly-shooting-in-the-air-near-race-track-during-preakness</link>
      <description>A man has been arrested for allegedly shooting a gun in the air near the Pimlico Race Track during Preakness.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 19:29:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Rushaad Hayward</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/man-arrested-for-allegedly-shooting-in-the-air-near-race-track-during-preakness</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/man-arrested-for-allegedly-shooting-in-the-air-near-race-track-during-preakness">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>A man has been arrested for allegedly shooting a gun in the air near the Pimlico Race Track during Preakness. </p><p>Around 6:45 p.m., officers in their patrol car heard shots fired in the 5600 block of Key Avenue. </p><p>After speaking to witnesses in the area, they learned a man wearing a red shirt and carrying a YETI cup allegedly fired the gun.</p><p>Police found the man, later identified as Bernard Cunningham, and placed him under arrest after he initially tried to avoid officers. </p><p>Prior to the arrest, a handgun was recovered from his waistband.</p><p>Investigation revealed he had a handgun permit and later determined it was valid. </p><p>Police say detectives then reviewed surveillance video that showed Cunningham sitting on the steps of a house on Key Avenue, pulling out a gun and shooting 10 rounds into the air.</p><p>"It should be noted the concern for public safety due to the discharging which transpired approximately 100 yards to the Pimlico Race Track on the day of Preakness," police records say.</p><p>The records also note the several thousand people in attendance for the race. </p><p>Detectives say Cunningham "displayed several behavioral indicators consistent with being under the influence." This included slurred speech, glassy eyes and an alcohol smell coming from his breath. </p><p>Alcohol residue was found in Cunnigham's YETI cup as well. </p><p>Cunningham was later taken to Central Booking for processing. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Johns Hopkins baseball team one win away from College World Series</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/marylandsports/local-sports/johns-hopkins-baseball-team-one-win-away-from-college-world-series</link>
      <description>The Johns Hopkins men's baseball team extended their winning streak to 25 games with a 7-4 victory over Case Western Reserve University in game one of the NCAA Super Regional.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 03:34:51 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Xavier Wherry</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/marylandsports/local-sports/johns-hopkins-baseball-team-one-win-away-from-college-world-series</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/marylandsports/local-sports/johns-hopkins-baseball-team-one-win-away-from-college-world-series">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The Johns Hopkins men's baseball team extended their winning streak to 25 games with a 7-4 victory over Case Western Reserve University in game one of the NCAA Super Regional.</p><p>The Blue Jays jumped to an early 3-0 lead in the first inning before falling behind 4-3 after the Spartans scored four runs in the fourth inning. But the team's resilience once again proved to be the difference.</p><p>"Well, certainly attest to our resiliency because our players get, see we're behind and it seems to give us a little extra energy. Everybody starts pulling for one another and we get one or two hits and the momentum grows. I would prefer we didn't fall behind," said Bob Babb, head coach.</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  JHU baseball shines bright in game one of NCAA Super Regional   Johns Hopkins baseball team one win away from College World Series <p>Graduate student Kieren Collins pitched a complete game for Johns Hopkins, allowing just 4 runs on 8 hits.</p><p>"The cutter and changeup were both working really well and lean on the curveball a little bit too. You also just gotta give a lot of credit. Our defense played amazing, amazing. I mean, we turned more double plays than I remember. It was a lot of fun to watch and be a part of," Collins said.</p><p>"He pitched to our gameplan perfectly, didn't give up free bases, kept the ball in the yard, was just outstanding, gave us nine strong innings," said Babb.</p><p>After regaining the lead by scoring twice in the 7th inning and once in the 8th, the Blue Jays relied on their defense to secure the win. Right fielder Alex Shane made the play of the afternoon, robbing the Spartans of what would have been a clutch hit.</p><p>"I mean off the bat, it was going to be a tough play and just really trust my center fielder telling me where the wall was and at then jumped and you know we've practiced that a lot of times throughout the year," Shane said.</p><p>The Blue Jays need just one more win against Case Western Reserve University to advance to the College World Series. Game two of the NCAA Super Regional will be at Babb Field on Saturday at 11 am.</p>This story was reported by a journalist and has been converted to this platform with the assistance of AI. Our editorial team verifies all reporting on all platforms for fairness and accuracy.    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black bear spotted in Baltimore County, sources say</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/black-bear-spotted-in-baltimore-county-sources-say</link>
      <description>A spokesperson with the Maryland Department of Natural Resources told WMAR that the calls started to come in a few weeks ago when the bear was first spotted in the Pikesville and Randallstown areas.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 23:20:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Dominick Philippe-Auguste</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/black-bear-spotted-in-baltimore-county-sources-say</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/black-bear-spotted-in-baltimore-county-sources-say">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The The Maryland Department of Natural Resources confirmed reports of bear sightings in Baltimore County. </p><p>Gregg Bortz with DNR told WMAR that the calls started to come in a few weeks ago when the bear was first spotted in the Pikesville and Randallstown areas.</p><p>The bear appears to be about 1.5 years old and is likely dispersing, which means it is currently leaving where it was born in search of a new area to live. </p><p>Bortz said that this is not uncommon around this time of year and that DNR is not attempting to capture or relocate this bear, but will continue to monitor its movements. </p><p>He added that people should give these animals space and allow them to move through the area unobstructed. </p><p>Usually, black bears are timid and shy animals that are more likely to flee or climb a tree than be involved in a confrontation.</p><p>But, if the bear feels threatened or startled, it may respond in a different manner. </p><p>Bortz said eliminating food attractants such as garbage, bird feeders, and pet food is the simplest way to reduce the chances of a bear being attracted to your area. </p><p>He said the goal is for the bear to keep moving peacefully on its way to a new place in the wild. </p><p>"That's what it wants, and what we want."</p><p>Residents can report a bear sighting to a local Wildlife and Heritage office at 410-356-0941.</p><p>You can also call DNR's general wildlife line at 410-260-8540. </p><p>For more information on what to do when encountering a bear, click <a href="https://bearwise.org">here</a>. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mother suspects abuse led to daughter's murder in Pasadena</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/mother-suspects-abuse-led-to-daughters-murder-in-pasadena</link>
      <description>An autopsy has found a Pasadena woman found dead in early April died from blunt force trauma, and the victim's mother says she has no doubt who killed her.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 20:47:17 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Jeff Hager</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/mother-suspects-abuse-led-to-daughters-murder-in-pasadena</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/mother-suspects-abuse-led-to-daughters-murder-in-pasadena">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>When police responded to a report of an overdose at a house on Lorene Court in Pasadena in early April, they discovered 34-year-old Heather Beaver clinging to what would prove to be the final moments of her life.</p><p>An autopsy has since determined she died from blunt force trauma.</p><p><b>RELATED: </b><a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/homicide-investigation-underway-in-pasadena">Homicide investigation underway in Pasadena</a></p><p>Were not divulging, which part of her body at this point was affected by the trauma, said Marc Limansky of the Anne Arundel County Police Department, Right now, our detectives are looking at that and trying to piece together exactly what transpired either during the early morning hours of that day or the days leading up to that morning.</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  WATCH: Mother suspects abuse led to daughter's murder in Pasadena   Mother suspects abuse led to daughter's murder in Pasadena <p>Heathers grieving mother, Susan Beaver, is much more forthright about her injuries.</p><p>Once she got to the hospital, they seen her body was bruised from head to toe. She had a broken nose, broken fingers, bleeding in the brain, Beaver recounted.</p><p>She suspects her daughters boyfriend, who she claims had a long history of abusing her.</p><p>Beaver adds she had sent Heather for private mental counseling and to a shelter for abused women in the weeks leading up to her murder.</p><p>She made the awful mistake of getting in touch with him and he picked her up, I believe on a Tuesday, and then she was dead by Friday morning, Beaver told us.</p><p>Found dead where she had been staying with that boyfriend in the unfinished basement of his parents home.</p><p>I called him Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde.</p><p>Apparently, confirming her mothers dire prediction that she had tried so hard to prevent.</p><p>I told her every time that she would go back to him that he is going to kill you one day.</p><p>Anyone with information about this case or who might have seen Heather Beaver in the days leading up to her death is asked to call investigators at 410-222-4731.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding access to fully outdoor, nature-based preschools and child care programs</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/expanding-access-to-fully-outdoor-nature-based-preschools-and-child-care-programs</link>
      <description>Some families and educators swear by this non-traditional type of early education. But right now it's a luxury many families can't afford. A new state pilot program aims to change that.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 19:25:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Elizabeth Worthington</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/expanding-access-to-fully-outdoor-nature-based-preschools-and-child-care-programs</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/expanding-access-to-fully-outdoor-nature-based-preschools-and-child-care-programs">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Joey Pasco wouldn't have necessarily described his daughter Aurelia as the "outdoorsy" type before. Then his wife heard about this place, Notchcliff Nature Programs, in Glen Arm.</p><p>We knew it was all outdoors, and we thought - let's give it a try, he recalled thinking. And it's gone so well that we've been here for three years.</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  WATCH: Expanding access to fully outdoor, nature-based preschools/child care programs   Expanding access to fully outdoor, nature-based preschools/child care programs <p>And clearly Aurelia, who climbed a tree while we talk to her dad, has taken to the nature-based schooling as well.</p><p>Rather than having kids cooped up in a school that may or may not even have windows in the classroom, things like that, I think this is - there's something to being in nature and learning, especially at a younger age that you can't get in a building, Pasco told WMAR-2 News.</p><p>And when we say nature-based, we mean it. Barring a severe weather emergency, kids here are outside all day, year-round - rain, sleet, or shine. Monica Wiedel-Lubinski runs Notchcliff Nature Programs. She says outdoor education helps kids become more environmentally-conscious, more independent, and more resilient.</p><p>There's a study that talks about the kids of the 1980s. If you compare how strong they were, their bodies were compared to today's kids, it's very sad. A lot of that has to do with screen time and sedentary ways of thinking and learning, she said.</p><p>Wiedel-Lubinski is also the head of the Association for Nature-based Education. She advocates for this type of schooling all over the country, but here in Maryland, she had to push her efforts into high gear, because the State Department of Education hasnt recognized it as a valid form of early education. Problem is - plenty of nature-based programs exist throughout the state anyway, operating without a license.</p><p>They fly under the radar. And that's dangerous potentially for children, Wiedel-Lubinsky said, since such programs arent subject to regular inspections and other health and safety regulations by MSDE.</p><p>Its also why programs like Notchcliff can only operate part-time; if they went beyond a certain number of hours per week, theyd be in violation of state law.</p><p>And even for the programs that do everything by the book, no license means no state-funded subsidies or scholarships for families. Access to this kind of education becomes limited to those who can afford it.</p><p>It keeps this barrier in place for sort of haves and have-nots, Wiedel-Lubinski said. While this may not be the choice every family wants to make, it should be an option for any family that wants to make it.</p><p>That's why she and a team of other nature-based educators lobbied the state legislature to establish a pilot program for outdoor preschool and child care licensing. They were successful; the law went into effect in 2023, and the <a href="https://earlychildhood.marylandpublicschools.org/msde-accepting-applications-outdoor-child-care-pilot-program">pilot program</a> starts this fall.</p><p>You can read the bill that passed <a href="https://mgaleg.maryland.gov/mgawebsite/Legislation/Details/HB0525?ys=2023rs">here</a>. If you're an educator that wants to apply or learn more, click <a href="https://earlychildhood.marylandpublicschools.org/msde-accepting-applications-outdoor-child-care-pilot-program">here</a>. The deadline is May 30, about 5-10 will be selected. Priority will be given to programs serving a broad range of geographic areas.</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  An In Focus look at nature preschools around the country   In Focus look at nature preschools around the country <p>The Maryland Department of Education will use the program to investigate the benefits of nature-based education, submitting a final report to the governor in 2027 with recommendations for modifying or expanding it. </p><p>However, there's no funding attached to the pilot program. So educators like Wiedel-Lubinski continue to run their schools and daycares on their own. They do it because they believe in it.</p><p>There's decades of research about why this is so, so beneficial to physical, social, emotional wellness and nature connection itself. Ultimately we need young people to be caretakers of our planet.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How you can see our spectacular galaxy this weekend!</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/how-you-can-see-our-spectacular-galaxy-this-weekend</link>
      <description>The reason this weekend is right for it? The lunar phase, where the Earth is in its orbit, and the extra day.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 18:28:41 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Amanda Engel</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/how-you-can-see-our-spectacular-galaxy-this-weekend</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/how-you-can-see-our-spectacular-galaxy-this-weekend">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The conditions are just right for a holiday weekend light show! </p><p>As we head into Memorial Day weekend, PhD student Stephen Schmidt from the Johns Hopkins University Department of Astronomy and Physics tells us that if you're in the right spot, you could see the Milky Way galaxy this weekend.</p><p>The reason this weekend is right for it? The lunar phase, where the Earth is in its orbit, and the extra day. </p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  Hear how you can take a look at the Milky Way galaxy   How you can see our spectacular galaxy this weekend! <p>"When the moon is very bright, that can make seeing lots of stars, like the Milky Way, very difficult," says Schmidt. "But around Memorial Day weekend this year, there's going to be a new moon, which means that the Moon is not going to be up at night." </p><p>And it's the right time of the year to be looking for the Milky Way. </p><p>"It just so happens that this time of year is a great time to see the Milky Way, like at around midnight-ish, when it gets to be quite dark," he says. </p><p>The reason the extra day can be important is that you might want to drive a little ways, and potentially spend the night to see it. </p><p>"There are some.. dark sky sites that are great places to go see the stars, the Milky Way, planets, anything, at any time of year. But they can take several hours to get there," Schmidt tells WMAR-2 News. "So like, Assateague Island is a nice choice. It's pretty far away from light pollution." </p><p>For those not willing to make a several-hours long trek, you can check out a light pollution map. </p><p>"Generally, what you're going to want to look into is some kind of light pollution map to see where a darker part of the area is, to potentially be able to see the Milky Way," he adds. </p><p>Here are a couple of light pollution maps so you can plan: </p><p><a href="https://lightpollutionmap.app/">Light Pollution App</a></p><p><a href="https://www.lightpollutionmap.info/">Light Pollution Map</a></p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frederick County student tackles Scripps National Spelling Bee with math mindset</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/frederick-county-student-tackles-scripps-national-spelling-bee-with-math-mindset</link>
      <description>The Scripps National Spelling Bee is gearing up, with 243 competitors and four days of intense competition. And for one newcomer from Frederick County, spelling is a little like his favorite subject.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 17:09:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Linnea Hoover</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/frederick-county-student-tackles-scripps-national-spelling-bee-with-math-mindset</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/frederick-county-student-tackles-scripps-national-spelling-bee-with-math-mindset">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The Scripps National Spelling Bee is gearing up, with 243 competitors and four days of intense competition. And for one newcomer from Frederick County, spelling is a little like his favorite subject.</p><p>I try to view it like math, you know, because thats where I feel like my strong suit is," says eighth-grade competitor Arya Bhavansikar. "When I'm up there, I just think of it like, you know, math, like how words can be formed with roots and then how it's just addition  just combining it all together to form one root, the linking letters.</p><p>Bhavansikar may be competing for the first time, but he already has a system that works for him  honing in on strategies for success.</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  WATCH: Frederick County student talks participating in Scripps National Spelling Bee   Frederick County student tackles Scripps National Spelling Bee with math mindset <p>I've been focusing on the roots as well as words considering that this is my first time," Bhavansikar said. "I haven't done this for a long time, so I'm just trying to hit specific areas where I think it's important. Like, I've watched some of the spelling bees and I try to find patterns in what they decide to choose.</p><p>But don't let his system fool you; he spends hours studying every day. And like every kid, he knows the importance of taking breaks.</p><p>I thought there would be a lot more kids that worked a lot harder, longer than me, who put more dedication and time into this." Bhavansikar said. "But yeah, I'm here and I'm grateful for the opportunity.</p><p>Bhavansikar expects the competition to be intense but says hes proud to share the stage with other contestants.</p><p>Just being up there alone is an honor," Bhavansikar said. "I might feel a little bit exhausted at the end, but just knowing to be up there will probably overshadow that feeling.</p><p>The Scripps National Spelling Bee is a four-day event starting May 27 and ending on the 29.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police investigating after a body was found in Brooklyn Park</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/police-investigating-after-a-body-was-found-in-brooklyn-park</link>
      <description>Anne Arundel County Police are on the scene of a suspicious death in the area of Disney Avenue and Alley 79 in Brooklyn Park.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 14:53:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Rushaad Hayward</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/police-investigating-after-a-body-was-found-in-brooklyn-park</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/police-investigating-after-a-body-was-found-in-brooklyn-park">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Anne Arundel County Police are investigating after a dead body was found on the ground in the area of Disney Avenue and Alley 79 in Brooklyn Park.</p><p>Police say the body belonged to a woman, with apparent trauma to her body.</p><p>The woman, who was later identified as 44-year-old Sarah Bundy, has been transported to the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner in Baltimore for an autopsy.</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  Hear neighbors react after a woman was found dead in Brooklyn Park   Police investigating after a body was found in Brooklyn Park <p>A neighbor in the community who declined to show her face or reveal her name told WMAR-2 News when she thinks about the discovery, she thinks back to what she heard the night before.</p><p>"I did hear a gentleman and a younger sounding woman screaming at the top of their lungs coming down the street. Usually there's people going up and down so I didn't think too much of it," she said.</p><p>When she found out why police were on her street Friday morning, she was left almost speechless.</p><p>"Honestly at first we were shocked, a little bit confused. I kind of beat myself up of not being that nosy neighbor and look out the window yesterday because I feel like I could've assisted if that was related at all."</p><p>She said with a corner store at the entrance of the community, there's usually a lot of traffic up and down the street but it's always friendly.</p><p>"Especially now that it's getting warmer outside people go get an ice cream you know a snack, it's not uncommon especially teenagers, there's a lot of bikes going up and down so it's a very family oriented neighborhood."</p><p>With that in mind, she said Friday's discovery doesn't make her feel unsafe.</p><p>"It doesn't make me uncomfortable to live here. I think anywhere in general you need to be wary nowadays so I don't think it should deter anyone from being in the area but you should always be mindful."</p><p>Police have since arrested Bundy's husband, 49-year-old Cedric Dion Calloway, in connection to this incident. </p><p>Detectives ask that anyone with information that could help this investigation contact them at 410-222-4731.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Evening News Headlines for Friday, May 23</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/top-evening-news-headlines-for-friday-may-23</link>
      <description>We're at the end of another week! More sunshine is expected today, with only an isolated shower chance across our northern suburbs during the afternoon/early-evening hours.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 14:23:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>WMAR Staff</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/top-evening-news-headlines-for-friday-may-23</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/top-evening-news-headlines-for-friday-may-23">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>We're at the end of another week! <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/weather/drying-out-heading-into-the-holiday-weekend">More sunshine is expected today,</a> with only an isolated shower chance across our northern suburbs during the afternoon/early-evening hours. Memorial Day weekend will feature dry skies with plenty of sunshine from Saturday through Monday.</p><p>Here are your top news headlines: </p> <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/funeral-services-announced-for-baltimore-city-firefighter-mark-dranbauer-jr">Funeral services announced for Baltimore City firefighter Mark Dranbauer Jr.</a> Naval Academy class of 2025 gets their moment to walk across the stage for graduation Baltimore City pools will be open this weekend! Top Evening News Headlines for Friday, May 23    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teen arrested in connection to a kidnapping involving a 12-year-old</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/teen-arrested-in-connection-to-a-kidnapping-involving-a-12-year-old</link>
      <description>Baltimore Police have arrested a teen in connection with a kidnapping and robbery involving a 12-year-old in East Baltimore.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 13:46:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Rushaad Hayward</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/teen-arrested-in-connection-to-a-kidnapping-involving-a-12-year-old</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/teen-arrested-in-connection-to-a-kidnapping-involving-a-12-year-old">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Baltimore Police have arrested a teen in connection with a kidnapping and robbery involving a 12-year-old in East Baltimore. </p><p>On May 19, the 12-year-old was walking to school in the 2500 block of Aisquith Street when he was approached by three suspects who implied they were armed. </p><p>Police say the suspects announced a robbery but the victim refused to hand over his things. </p><p>As a result, the suspects forced the 12-year-old into a nearby home, where they assaulted the victim and stole his phone and shoes. </p><p>Detectives quickly identified one of the suspects involved, learning he was under electronic monitoring due to prior involvement in several other incidents. </p><p>He was taken to the Juvenile Justice Center where he was charged with armed robbery and kidnapping. </p><p>This incident remains under investigation. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memorial Day Weekend Planner</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/memorial-day-weekend-planner</link>
      <description>We finally get a break from the rain this weekend, and there are a bunch of events to go to. Here's a look at your weekend planner.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 13:11:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Cameron McMillian</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/memorial-day-weekend-planner</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/memorial-day-weekend-planner">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>1. There are three ceremonies in Howard county. </p><p>Things kick off tomorrow at Ellicott citys VFW post, starting at 12 P.M.</p><p>On Sunday, American Legion Post 156 is hosting a remembrance service at St. John's Episcopal church at noon. And on Monday, there's a ceremony at the Harriet Tubman cultural center in Columbia. That starts at 8 A.M.</p><p>2. Annapolis has its Memorial Day parade on Monday, it starts at 10 AM in the downtown area. There's also a Memorial Day concert at Beth El Memorial Park in Randallstown on Monday. That begins at 11 AM.</p><p>3. Enjoy craft beer amongst the animals at the Maryland Zoo. <a href="https://www.marylandzoo.org/special_events/brew-at-the-zoo/?gad_source=1&amp;gad_campaignid=22479123523&amp;gbraid=0AAAAADjNc-vjFnwhK0AJO2pw7JvNX2Xb2&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwucDBBhDxARIsANqFdr1fLg21O0CzdK8Dx2N5SPRXzgmOfiCUC1q_sLG3iEkscbcCV4lrbpMaAjgCEALw_wcB">Brew at the Zoo</a> is tomorrow and Sunday. You can sample more than 80 craft beers, wines, and hard seltzers. There's also live bands, food, and your admission to the zoo is included in the ticket price.</p><p> 4. <a href="https://www.visithowardcounty.com/event/saturday-farmers-markets-on-main/23174/">The Old Ellicott City farmer's market</a> opens this weekend. It runs every Saturday at Tiber park from 9 AM until 1 PM. The market will be open through October 25th.</p><p>5. <a href="https://www.sowebofest.org/">The Sowebo Arts and Music festival</a> is this Sunday at the Hollins Market. There will be dozens of art, craft and non-profit vendors, plus a kids alley.</p><p> 6. The Maryland Plant Festival takes over Silver Spring. It's a three day festival starting tomorrow 10 AM until 4 PM . There will be a variety of plants, food, and small businesses. This is free event, but you'll need to reserve a spot. <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/maryland-plant-fest-tickets-1310450726399">Click here to reserve one. </a></p><p>7. <a href="https://mountrainiermd.org/391/Mount-Rainier-Day-2025">The Mount Rainier Day Festival</a> celebrates its 115th anniversary tomorrow. There will be arts and crafts, local vendors, and activities for all ages to enjoy. It runs from 11AM until 4 PM.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longtime Baltimore sportswriter Jim Henneman dies</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/longtime-baltimore-sportswriter-jim-henneman-dies</link>
      <description>The Orioles on Friday released a statement expressing heartbreak over the passing of longtime Baltimore sportswriter Jim Henneman.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 13:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Amanda Engel</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/longtime-baltimore-sportswriter-jim-henneman-dies</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/longtime-baltimore-sportswriter-jim-henneman-dies">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The Orioles on Friday released a statement expressing heartbreak over the passing of longtime Baltimore sportswriter Jim Henneman. </p><p>"Henny's friendly demeanor, words of wisdom, and historical anecdotes will be dearly missed," writes the team. "We are all better for knowing him and are eternally grateful for his dedication to the Orioles for more than eight decades." </p><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/2a/87/ab0cef1d431d8fffe37dad041e6f/img-8844.jpeg"></figure><p>In January 2024, the Orioles renamed the press box at Camden Yards for Henneman. </p><p>"The Camden Yards' press box will forever bear his name and be a welcoming place to remember and recognize his life and legacy," the Orioles said in a statement. </p><p>He published a book about the Orioles in 2015, called "Baltimore Orioles: 60 Years of Orioles Magic." </p><p>Henneman was 89. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Fantasia to Frenchie: Artscape delivers range and special performances with Artscape after Dark</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/homepage-showcase/from-fantasia-to-frenchie-artscape-delivers-range-and-special-performances-with-artscape-after-dark</link>
      <description>Grammy-nominated vocalist and theatrical performer Frenchie Davis chats with the Good Morning Maryland team about her performances scheduled for Artscape weekend.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 12:42:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Kara Burnett</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/homepage-showcase/from-fantasia-to-frenchie-artscape-delivers-range-and-special-performances-with-artscape-after-dark</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/homepage-showcase/from-fantasia-to-frenchie-artscape-delivers-range-and-special-performances-with-artscape-after-dark">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>One of Baltimores biggest festivals, Artscape, returns this weekend. Its a two-day celebration showcasing both national and local talentfrom visual art to live music.</p><p>This years festival features around 50 local performers and a star-studded lineup throughout the weekend. Headliners include LeToya Luckett, Fantasia, Robin Thicke, and Baltimores own American Idol contestant, Gabby Samone.</p><p>Also taking the stage is Broadway powerhouse Frenchie Davis.</p><p>I love that the event is free to the public because art should be accessible to everybody, Davis said. I also believe strongly that art is a big part of how we foster a stronger sense of community, especially for us melanated people. That is how we have kept our stories alive, that is how we have lifted one another up. That's how we've survivedand we will survive continually.</p><p>Davis, known for her theatrical credits in Rent, Dreamgirls, and Cinderella Enchanted, will perform this weekend at Hotel Ulysses in Mount Vernon.</p><p>They can come prepared to laugh, sing along and dance, said Davis.</p><p>We're partnering with Hotel Ulysses for an Artscape after Dark series, and were excited to bring Frenchie Davis as part of this programming, said Tonya Miller Hall, Mayors Senior Adviser of Arts &amp; Culture. Shell be performing on Saturday and Sunday in the Bloom Room at Hotel Ulysses.</p><p>Frenchie Davis will also headline Echo Stage on Sunday.</p><p>Artscape will take place May 2425, from 11:00 AM to 10:00 PM at 100 Holliday Street, in Downtown Baltimore. Check out the <a href="https://www.artscape.org/performers-schedule/djs-performers/">full list </a>of the 2025 Artscape performers. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NaTori Aliyah’s Homecoming plans to hit the right notes at Artscape 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/natori-aliyahs-homecoming-plans-to-hit-the-right-notes-at-artscape-2025</link>
      <description>The Artscape stage in Baltimore has seen its share of talent—but when NaTori Aliyah got the call that she would step into the spotlight, it was clear: she was going to have something to prove.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 12:32:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Randall Newsome</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/natori-aliyahs-homecoming-plans-to-hit-the-right-notes-at-artscape-2025</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/natori-aliyahs-homecoming-plans-to-hit-the-right-notes-at-artscape-2025">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The </p>Artscape<p> stage in Baltimore has seen its share of talentbut when NaTori Aliyah got the call that she would step into the spotlight, it was clear: she was going to have something to prove.</p><p>Youre gonna see how much Ive learnedand everything Ive learned, Im gonna leave it on the floor.NaTori is no stranger to the stage. Shes traveled the world as a professional dancer, but this performance is set to be her coming out party as a musician and to peopleespecially in her hometown  that she had the vocals to match her moves.</p><p>I definitely want them to think, Great performer, but lets not forgetyour girl can sing. The mic will be on.</p><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/4f/b3/045953ae4da2a2f3ff1593026a27/natori-aliyah-artscape-2.jpg"></figure>A New Chapter in Her Career<p>Locked in and laser-focused, NaTori poured her heart into the performancebut she also brought a surprise.</p><p>She plans to debut a brand-new songa track deeply inspired by the energy and rhythm of Baltimore club music.</p><p>If you are a lover of club music, if youre a lover of club dance, rockin off, cuttin upthe whole nineyoure gonna love this song. If you understand club culture, youll appreciate it.</p>Family First, Dreams Second<p>As the spotlight burned bright, NaTori remained grounded in her purposeher family and the journey that led her to this moment.</p><p>I do it for them first, and then everything else will fall into place. Im really excited for my family to see me in this light, and for everyone to see that the labor was not in vain.But maybe the most emotional part of her performance comes when she things about who it was really for: her 8-year-old self.</p><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/18/db/1acec29e42c89d39ae924376262a/natori-aliyah-artscape-1.jpg"></figure><p>Ill be talking to my 8-year-old selfthe girl who always dreamed of being on stage but was too shy or scared to say she wanted to sing.</p>A Homegrown Beginning to a Global Journey<p>Before she hits big stages across the country, NaToris proud that her next chapter began right at home.</p><p>It feels good to start home. Everything is aligning the way its supposed to. I needed to be here first. Once I show God Ill do what I gotta do in my home, I think Hell bless me with more.With the </p>Artscape<p> crowd behind her, NaTori Aliyah is already looking aheadto dropping an EP and building her catalog. But for now, shes basking in the moment that proves she's exactly where she's supposed to be.</p><p>You can search for her singles, </p>"Sway,"<p> and </p>"Forever's at an End" <p> on Apple Music. You can also follow her page on Instagram </p>@NaToriAliyah.<figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/06/08/f6d902824eafa9bd7052ee567b0e/natori-artscape-3.jpg"></figure>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artscape introduces new Film program for 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/artscape-introduces-new-film-program-for-2025</link>
      <description>From short films to documentaries, including films like Baltimore Boys and The Body Politic, will air all day on Saturday at the Baltimore Center Stage.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ja Nai Wright</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/artscape-introduces-new-film-program-for-2025</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/artscape-introduces-new-film-program-for-2025">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>This year, Artscape has a number of changes. There is a new location, the event is earlier in the year, and now there is a new type of art on display.</p><p>"Its a new program track called Beyond the Reels where theyre giving, filmmakers, people in TV professionals, a chance to actually screen a film here," says Larry 'whaddup' Caudle.</p><p>From short films to documentaries, including films like Baltimore Boys and The Body Politic, will air all day on Saturday at the Baltimore Center Stage.</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  Hear Larry Caudle speak on the film that will screen during Artscape 2025   Artscape introduces new Film program for 2025 <p>Larry Caudle has worked on the film More Than Hype for a number of years.</p><p>It's about the history of Baltimore's club music.</p><p>Hes had a few screenings in the last two years, including at the Maryland Film Festival.</p><p>"So its a different response from everybody, but for the majority, um, the masses have, uh, taken on this, uh, film. Its been really overwhelming, you know, to just get that respect and love from everybody else," say Caudle</p><p>But he says this Artscape screening will be the largest screening so far.</p><p>He says he is proud to show off a different side of Baltimore City.</p><p>"You always hear about the dirt bikes and 12 oclock and the squeegee boys, but this film highlights the culture and the legends that started the sound," says Caudle.</p><p>Larry Caudle said he is excited that Artscape has added a film element this year.</p><p>"Everything that we do in film is art, you know, from the shots, from writing the script to coloring, to wardrobe, to, casting, its all a form of art. It was its just a blessing to be, a part of this inaugural program during this time."</p><p>For a full schedule of screenings and more information on the Beyond the Rails program, visit <a href="http://artscape.org">artscape.org</a>.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Loyola School in Baltimore to expand to a new building while maintaining small class sizes</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/the-loyola-school-in-baltimore-to-expand-to-a-new-building-while-maintaining-small-class-sizes</link>
      <description>The Loyola School, a Jesuit preschool and elementary school, is expanding to a new building in Mt. Vernon.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Megan Knight</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/the-loyola-school-in-baltimore-to-expand-to-a-new-building-while-maintaining-small-class-sizes</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/the-loyola-school-in-baltimore-to-expand-to-a-new-building-while-maintaining-small-class-sizes">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Sharon Wheaden-West is right at home in her first grade classroom at the Loyola School. Before coming here, she taught for 25 years with Baltimore City Schools.</p><p>"It's a big difference, our classroom sizes are much smaller," she said. </p><p>At city schools, Wheaden-West would have around 25 students in her class. At the Loyola School, she has 9 students this year.</p><p>She is also an ordained minister and the Jesuit roots of the school allow her to share her faith with her students.</p><p>"In public schools you have to keep that separate so it was awful hard when sometimes you wanted to pray with them or things like that," she said. "But here Im free to be able to pray with them and free to talk about life and God and things like that so it just makes me complete as an educator. I can be who I am."</p><p>Perhaps one of the biggest differences is the year-round school model. Kindergarten teacher Melissa Walker thinks it's a big plus.</p><p>"It helps me see where my students strengths are and where I need to push them further," she said.</p><p>Right now, the school is taking up every available square inch at the St. Ignatius Church on Calvert Street while they wait for their new school to open.</p><p>"Were so thankful to the church to house us but Im looking forward to setting up writing centers and areas for my kids to be able to go and work and move around," said Wheaden-West.</p><p>They won't have to go far. Five rowhomes across Madison Street are being transformed into the new school. They were once used as housing for teachers at the all-boys St. Ignatius Loyola Academy, which is now in Federal Hill. Both schools were founded by Father William Watters, who also started the co-ed Cristo Rey Jesuit High School.</p><p>"[Father Watters] noticed that so many students going into St. Ignatius and Cristo Rey were 2 or 3 grade levels behind in English and math, and he thought let's get them a strong foundation, let's get them early and help them build," said James Fiore, the president of the Loyola School.</p><p>The school opened in 2017 with 18, 2-year-olds. Each year, except for one due to COVID-19, they've added a grade level. In the fall, they will add the fourth grade for the start of the new school year.</p><p>"While we will get bigger and have more students and serve more students, were going to make sure we have that tight-knit family atmosphere that is so important to us," said Fiore.</p><p>Parents who apply to the school are asked to pay a $40 monthly fee. The rest of the tuition is covered by donations and grants. Parents are also asked to volunteer 10 hours a semester, participate in workshops and commit to the Loyola School for eight years.</p><p>"Because we want to see that growth," said Fiore. "We have so much time to spend with them and help them build that strong foundation."</p><p>As the finishing touches are put in place at the new building, excitement is growing about the new possibilities.</p><p>"Knowing that it use to be homes, and then it was nothing, and now we see classrooms and the different spaces. It's kind of a dream come true and Im blessed to be a part of it," said Walker.</p><p>Fiore said they hope to officially open the new building this summer and move the students in for the start of the new school year in the fall.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gusty winds along with sunshine Saturday</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/weather/drying-out-heading-into-the-holiday-weekend</link>
      <description>Winds could gust up and over 30 mph heading into Saturday, along with more sunshine. The weather will be dry this weekend.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 06:34:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Abigail Degler</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/weather/drying-out-heading-into-the-holiday-weekend</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/weather/drying-out-heading-into-the-holiday-weekend">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Finally, after a stretch of cloudy and cool weather, the sunshine returns for Saturday. </p><p>There will be some low clouds that try to take over as we go into the afternoon, but we aren't expecting any rain. The one nuisance that we have to contend with will be the wind. As of now, we expect gusts up to 30 mph Saturday, and as high as 25 mph Sunday. The dry weather continues into the start of next week, with the nicest day being Memorial Day. The latest run of the forecast models still indicate rain arriving on Tuesday, but each model run pushes back the onset of precipitation. I'd expect a dry Tuesday morning, with showers arriving late Tuesday night. Wednesday will bring the heaviest precipitation next week. </p><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/3d/84/b10dbfa94f0da542802f10d1cc90/7-day.JPG"></figure><p><b>7 Day Forecast:</b></p><p><b>Tonight </b>Mostly clear, with a low around 49. West wind 5-10 mph, with gusts as high as 20 mph.</p><p><b>Saturday </b>Partly cloudy, with a high near 70. </p><p><b>Saturday Night </b>Mostly clear, with a low around 49.</p><p><b>Sunday </b>Mostly sunny, with a high near 72.</p><p><b>Sunday Night </b>Partly cloudy, with a low around 52.</p><p><b>Memorial Day </b>Partly cloudy, with a high near 74.</p><p><b>Monday Night </b>Mostly cloudy, with a low around 56.</p><p><b>Tuesday </b>Mostly cloudy, with a high near 70. </p><p><b>Tuesday Night </b>Showers likely. Mostly cloudy, with a low around 58. </p><p><b>Wednesday </b>A chance of showers. Mostly cloudy, with a high near 71. </p><p><b>Wednesday Night </b>A chance of showers. Mostly cloudy, with a low around 59. </p><p><b>Thursday </b>A chance of showers. Partly sunny, with a high near 74.</p><p><b>Thursday Night </b>A chance of showers. Mostly cloudy, with a low around 59. </p><p><b>Friday </b>A chance of showers and thunderstorms. Partly sunny, with a high near 80.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Coppin State women's basketball coach brings Power 5 experience and winning pedigree to rebuild program</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/new-coppin-state-womens-basketball-coach-brings-power-5-experience-and-winning-pedigree-to-rebuild-program</link>
      <description>The new coach expressed pride in his journey from Chester, Pennsylvania, to coaching at the highest levels of college basketball.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 03:13:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Xavier Wherry</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/new-coppin-state-womens-basketball-coach-brings-power-5-experience-and-winning-pedigree-to-rebuild-program</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/new-coppin-state-womens-basketball-coach-brings-power-5-experience-and-winning-pedigree-to-rebuild-program">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Darrell Mosley has been named the new head coach of Coppin State University's women's basketball team, bringing extensive collegiate coaching experience to a program coming off its most successful season in years.</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  WATCH: Former Arizona State coach takes helm of Coppin State women's basketball    Former Arizona State coach takes helm of Coppin State women's basketball <p>Mosley, who most recently served as associate head coach at Arizona State University, has over 15 years of collegiate coaching experience. His most successful stint was at Lincoln University, where he won 82 games as head coachthe second most in that program's history.</p><p>"Kinda had to work my way up the ladder until my name was called again to be a head coach," Mosley said.</p><p>The new coach expressed pride in his journey from Chester, Pennsylvania, to coaching at the highest levels of college basketball.</p><p>"Coaching against Pac-12 coaches and Big 12, I never thought or imagined growing up as a kid from Chester, PA to say I've coached at the Power 5 ranks, Power 4 ranks, and even Division 1. I think this was the final box to check in my career," Mosley said.</p><p>Mosley takes over a Coppin State program that reached the postseason for the first time since 2009.</p><p>"Me being the MEAC and the HBCU guy, I always tip my hat off because I know what the resources are like to have to prepare and play against these other mid-major Power five teams," he said.</p><p>The roster rebuild will be significant, as Mosley noted there's currently only one returning player.</p><p>"This is where the transfer portal comes in in my favor, you know, when you have a late hire," Moseley said. "And you know, one returner, a couple of freshmen that were signed to the previous coach so kinda gotta get a chance to learn them and go watch film on them and see what they can add value on."</p><p>While next season's schedule is still being finalized, one notable matchup is already generating excitementa game against South Carolina and legendary head coach Dawn Staley.</p><p>"To be able to coach against a legend, a national champion, multiple national champion, and then even on the weekend that occurs on Martin Luther King weekend, so he had a dream and talking about having a dream, having a dream to coach against Dawn Staley is just a remarkable opportunity that I'm grateful to be able to have," Mosley said.</p><p><b>This story was reported by a journalist and has been converted to this platform with the assistance of AI. Our editorial team verifies all reporting on all platforms for fairness and accuracy.</b></p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18-year-old shot and killed two weeks before graduation</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/18-year-old-shot-and-killed-two-weeks-before-graduation</link>
      <description>Demetrius Phyall, or Meechie, was only two weeks away from graduating high school with his whole life ahead of him when he was shot and killed.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 02:49:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Raven Payne</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/18-year-old-shot-and-killed-two-weeks-before-graduation</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/18-year-old-shot-and-killed-two-weeks-before-graduation">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Demetrius Phyall, or Meechie, was only two weeks away from graduating high school with his whole life ahead of him when he was shot and killed.</p><p>"I guess, what if?"</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  WATCH: 18-year-old shot and killed two weeks before graduation    18-year-old shot and killed two weeks before graduationDemetrius Phyall (Meechie) <p>That's the question Delegate Sean A. Stinnett is left asking himself after 18-year-old Demetrius Phyall, or Menchie's, life was killed.</p><p>Stinnett has known Demetrius since he was 3 years old.</p><p>"He's just like one of my own little kids, you know, me being the big uncle," Stinnett said. "I've watched him grow up since him, his brother, and my youngest daughter grew up pretty much in kiddie college at Baltimore City Community College."</p><p>He told WMAR 2 News that he matured into a young man with goals and ambitions.</p><p>"He was a kid that was trying to find his way in life. He reestablished himself as far as being close to God and establish his faith in Islam."</p><p>But those goals were tragically cut short on Monday.</p><p>Baltimore City Police say around 5:40 p.m. officers responded to East Preston Street to investigate several ShotSpotter alerts.</p><p>Demetrius was found shot multiple times.</p><p>He later died at the hospital.</p><p>Stinnett learned of his passing while at a meeting.</p><p>"[I felt] devastated, angry, hurtnot only that a young child lost his life, but also you're concerned about his parents because I know how much his parents really loved him as well."</p><p>The way he died hit Stinnett even harder considering Demetrius was a part of the Baltimore Clean Streets program.</p><p>One of its main focuses is on mediating members of the youth to prevent arguments from resulting in crimes.</p><p>"Overall, I think that we just have to find ways to do a little bit more to make sure that we reach to those individuals that are establishing these types of beefs."</p><p>He said Demetrius was so close to starting a new chapter in his life.</p><p>"He was two weeks away from graduating from high school, and then he wanted to get his CDL license, and that's something that I was going to gift to him," he said. "We're not gonna see the progression; we're not gonna be able to see him get married and have children and give more smiles to other people."</p><p>There's no suspect information at this time.</p><p>If you know anything about this shooting, use the Metro Crime Stoppers tip line.</p><p>Demetrius's funeral will be held on Saturday.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BPD to increase patrols around synagogues following D.C. shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/bpd-to-increase-patrols-around-synagogues-following-d-c-shooting</link>
      <description>The Baltimore Police Department announced it'll be increasing patrols and police presence around synagogues, community centers and other key areas around the city.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 22:22:51 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Rushaad Hayward</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/bpd-to-increase-patrols-around-synagogues-following-d-c-shooting</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/bpd-to-increase-patrols-around-synagogues-following-d-c-shooting">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The Baltimore Police Department announced it'll be increasing patrols and police presence around synagogues, community centers and other key areas around the city.</p><p>This comes after two two Israeli Embassy staff members were shot and killed outside the Capital Jewish Museum in Washington, D.C.</p><p>"While there are currently no known threats to our area, we are taking these proactive steps out of an abundance of caution to ensure the safety and security of all residents," Police Commissioner Richard Worley said in a statement.</p><p>The man accused of Wednesday night's shooting now faces multiple counts of murder and federal firearms charges. </p><p>Elias Rodriguez, 30, was detained Wednesday night at the Capital Jewish Museum, where he allegedly shouted Free, free Palestine."</p><p>Officers responded to reports of a shooting around 9:08 p.m., and found an unresponsive man and woman. Both were pronounced dead at the scene.</p><p>The victims were identified as Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Milgrim, a couple who authorities said were exiting the museum when they were shot.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Before it's too late": Morrell Park neighbors say more speed deterrents needed</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/infocus/before-its-too-late-morrell-park-neighbors-say-more-speed-deterrents-needed</link>
      <description>"I've done seen numerous pets get hit. I've almost been hit a few times myself. I just know that it's gonna end up eventually being somebody's child," neighbor Charlie Monroe said.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 21:49:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Blair Sabol</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/infocus/before-its-too-late-morrell-park-neighbors-say-more-speed-deterrents-needed</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/infocus/before-its-too-late-morrell-park-neighbors-say-more-speed-deterrents-needed">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Herkimer Street in the Morrell Park neighborhood is usually quiet. That is, until a car goes whizzing by.</p><p>The speed limit is 15 miles per hour. But numerous videos provided to WMAR-2 News show drivers don't seem to be following the rules of the road. </p><p>"I've done seen numerous pets get hit. I've almost been hit a few times myself. I just know that it's gonna end up eventually being somebody's child," neighbor Charlie Monroe said. Im just hoping that something gets done before it's too late.</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  Hear Morrell Park neighbors voice their concerns in regards to speeding in the area   Morrell Park neighbors say more speed deterrents needed <p>Monroe says he and other neighbors have wanted speed bumps for decades as drivers have used the street as a cut through to avoid traffic on Washington Boulevard.</p><p>"You can count on 10 cars in 10 minutes flying down here because they're beating the red light," neighbor Wayne Veit said.</p><p>Though DOT does not have any record of a speed study on the street, Veit remembers seeing and speaking to a city employee on site about 10 years ago to check out if speed deterrents were needed.</p><p>But he says it was the wrong time.</p><p>"So, the guy is sitting there and I says, well, you gotta be here in the afternoon or on the weekend. Oh no, the city does not pay me overtime. If nobody gets speeding here during lunchtime or whatever, then we're not gonna do it," Veit said. "But that don't make no sense."</p><p>Baltimore DOT representative Kathy Dominick says a speed study on Herkimer Street is being expedited and is expected to be completed by the end of this week, weather permitting.</p>   &lt;a href='#'&gt;&lt;img alt='Traffic Calming Requests to 311 ' src='https:&amp;#47;&amp;#47;public.tableau.com&amp;#47;static&amp;#47;images&amp;#47;Tr&amp;#47;TrafficCalmingRequeststhroughMay222025&amp;#47;TrafficCalmingRequeststo311&amp;#47;1_rss.png' style='border: none' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;    <p>Last year, Baltimore DOT installed 145 speed humps.</p><p>The agency considers factors like vehicle speeds, crash history, proximity to schools, parks and nursing homes as well as roadway geometric considerations for speed hump installation.</p><p>Since 2022, the city has received thousands of similar requests through 311 for traffic calming measures which includes speed humps, but also speed limit signage and lane narrowing as well.</p><p>It can take 90 business days for a speed study to be completed, but the agency acknowledges due to the significant volume of requests they do not always meet that deadline "though we strive to" DOT reported to WMAR-2 News via email.</p><p>BCDOT encourages residents to <a href="http://balt311.baltimorecity.gov/citizen/s/">always submit traffic calming requests through 311</a>.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anne Arundel County school meal prices remain unchanged, saving families' budgets</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/anne-arundel-county-school-meals-prices-remain-unchanged-saving-families-budgets</link>
      <description>The Board of Education of Anne Arundel County says the price of school meals, along with reduced-price breakfast and meals, will not be going up.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 21:31:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Travis Case</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/anne-arundel-county-school-meals-prices-remain-unchanged-saving-families-budgets</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/anne-arundel-county-school-meals-prices-remain-unchanged-saving-families-budgets">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>A win for the plates of Anne Arundel County School students and the pockets of their parents.</p><p>The Board of Education of Anne Arundel County says the price of school meals, along with reduced-price breakfast and meals, will not be going up.</p><p>For a decade, breakfast has been $1.50, elementary school lunches have been $2.75, and middle school lunches have been $3.00.</p><p>Milk prices will also stay at 55 cents.</p><p>According to AACPS (Anne Arundel County Public Schools), the school systems Division of Food and Nutrition Services gets 73% of its funding from federal reimbursements, 22% from meal sales, and 4% from the State of Maryland.</p><p>What Director of Food &amp; Nutrition Services Jodi Risse and her team have done to maintain the price structure for our school meals for so long is nothing short of amazing, Superintendent of Schools Dr. Mark Bedell said. There is so much uncertainty in our economy now, and the fact that we can provide this stability for our families is a huge step toward helping all students Belong, Grow, and Succeed.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Jewish leaders react to D.C. shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/local-jewish-leaders-react-to-d-c-shooting</link>
      <description>26 year-old Sarah Milgrim and 30 year-old Yaron Lischinsky were leaving an event hosted by the American Jewish Committee when a gunman shot and killed them.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 21:28:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Elizabeth Worthington</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/local-jewish-leaders-react-to-d-c-shooting</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/local-jewish-leaders-react-to-d-c-shooting">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The amount of investment the Jewish community has to make in security measures is "phenomenal," according to Howard Libit, executive director for the Baltimore Jewish Council. And Wednesday night's deadly shooting outside the Capital Jewish Museum in Washington D.C. serves as further proof of why it continues to be necessary.</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  WATCH: Jewish leaders react to the shooting   Local Jewish leaders react to D.C. shooting <p>"Most synagogues, in addition to dues, have added a special assessment for security because it's so expensive. If you show up at an event and there's not an armed guard, you're looking around like where are they? Are they just down the hall in the bathroom or did someone forget to order security? I mean that's where we are now," Libit told WMAR-2 News. </p><p>"This is the reality of being a Jew in America or really anywhere around the world today. You go to a synagogue and you have to walk through a metal detector, like you're getting on an airplane, right? So there's always security, there's always a a baseline recognition that something could happen," Julie Rayman, managing director of policy and political affairs for the American Jewish Committee, said.</p><p>26 year-old Sarah Milgrim and 30 year-old Yaron Lischinsky were leaving an event hosted by the American Jewish Committee when a gunman shot and killed them. Police identified the suspect as 31-year-old Elias Rodriguez. He was heard shouting "free, free Palestine," as he was taken into custody.</p><p>"I was not there last night," Rayman said. "About 20 of my colleagues were, and I've spent the day talking to them about their experiences and what they saw, whether it was, you know, leaving and seeing sort of the crime scene, or even not knowingly, and then later knowingly, seeing the shooter himself."</p><p>Rayman says the sad irony is that the purpose of the event was to focus on bringing humanitarian aid to Gaza.</p><p>"It's an irony that unfortunately and strangely kind of keeps repeating, right? I'm wearing a a yellow ribbon for the hostages who are still in Gaza, and thinking about how so many of the victims on October 7, 2023 were the people who lived in the small communities in the kibbutzes close to Gaza, who were involved in efforts to promote peace, who would drive ill or injured Palestinians to Israeli hospitals and help with agricultural pursuits," she told WMAR-2 News. "So it seems to be happening over and over again that the people who are the most committed to peace are the ones who fall victim."</p><p>Rayman has been heartened by the messages of support that have come in from all over the world. "But at the same time, you go on social media and you see people glorifying this murder, you see calls for additional violence and it's normalized," she said. "It's now sort of what we come to expect on social media, because the bar is simply so low, and the bar can't be that low in America. It just can't. This was a horrible, horrible day for the Jewish community. But it was a horrible day for America."</p><p>For her, and for Libit here in Baltimore, they refuse to live in fear. </p><p>"AJC surveys American Jews every year to understand how they're experiencing anti-Semitism, and year after year over the last five years, more and more American Jews are saying that they're hiding parts of their identity because they're afraid of anti-Semitism," Rayman said. "In this last year, 56% said they changed something. They stopped wearing a Star of David or a yarmulke, didn't want to put a mezuzah on their door front, something like that, because they were afraid. And it reflects a very harsh reality, but it also reminds us that hiding isn't the solution. It can't be the solution. And that's not what's going to make our community strong and proud."</p><p>But they'll still double down on the efforts to keep themselves and their communities safe.</p><p>"Every time an incident like this happens, we keep rethinking it our director of security says, is there something more we need to do? Is there something more we need to invest in?" Libit said.</p><p>Israel's Foreign Minister is calling the shooting a terrorist attack. </p><p>Investigators are currently reviewing what appeared to be a manifesto that was posted on social media Wednesday, and has the suspect's name on it. They have not yet determined its authenticity.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dog days of adoption</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/the-dog-days-of-adoption</link>
      <description>As dog adoptions have trended downward across the country, one shelter is taking steps to land adult canines in forever homes and to keep current owners from surrendering them.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 21:13:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Jeff Hager</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/the-dog-days-of-adoption</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/the-dog-days-of-adoption">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Willamina, a pit bull mix, certainly wont turn down a snack, but she wants far more.</p><p>As the longest dog resident at the Humane Society of Harford County, Willamina has spent nine months here with no takers as the adoption rate for adult dogs has plummeted.</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  Check out these cute dogs   The dog days of adoption <p>In the first like four months of this year, weve taken in 417 dogs, said Erin Long, the nonprofits marketing manager, 302 have gotten adopted, which is great, but its just a drain on all of our resources.</p><p>While overall adoptions jumped by 19 percent last year over the previous year, dog adoptions dropped by more than eight percent, and its a similar story in shelters across the country.</p><p>I think it has everything to do with the economy, Long explained, People being able to find affordable housing and then, even if they do, a lot of landlords have breed restrictions so we are seeing all of that.</p><p>One way the shelter has addressed the fall off in adoptions is by helping dog owners keep from surrendering them in the first place.</p><p>Last year, visits to its pet food pantry jumped by over 50 percent and it distributed more than 17 hundred bags of food to help those who could not afford to feed them.</p><p>The shelter also has redoubled its efforts to place the existing animals holding adoption events like its Blowout Memorial Day Weekend, which runs from Friday through Sunday, and this treat is for you, since you can adopt any dog, including Willamina, for just 50 bucks.</p><p>Regularly its 160, and I do want people to know that still includes all their vaccinations, a microchip, their spay/neuter surgery, said Long, Thats all included for just 50 dollars.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baltimore-based youth charity ordered to halt fundraising amid allegations of fraud</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/baltimore-based-youth-charity-ordered-to-halt-fundraising-amid-allegations-of-fraud</link>
      <description>Maryland Attorney General Anthony Brown, along with Secretary of State Susan C. Lee, announced Thursday that DMV Futures, Inc. must cease fundraising amid allegations of fraud.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 21:06:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Dominick Philippe-Auguste</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/baltimore-based-youth-charity-ordered-to-halt-fundraising-amid-allegations-of-fraud</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/baltimore-based-youth-charity-ordered-to-halt-fundraising-amid-allegations-of-fraud">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Maryland Attorney General Anthony Brown, along with Secretary of State Susan C. Lee, announced Thursday that a Baltimore-based charity has been ordered to cease fundraising. </p><p>DMV Futures, Inc., along with its president, Marcus Smith, received a cease and desist order following allegations of unsupervised solicitation involving children. </p><p>According to officials, the youth charity is accused of driving groups of children into neighborhoods to engage in door-to-door solicitation to try and garner charitable contributions and sell candy. </p><p>An investigation revealed that the organization claimed to offer comprehensive work-educational youth programs and services, including part-time jobs, scholarships and other financial benefits to children. </p><p>Officials discovered that not only did the organization not have youth programs or services, none of the charitable contributions went towards benefiting the children. </p><p>The organizers allegedly pocketed the donations into their own personal accounts with no accounting control or board oversight. </p><p>Additionally, the annual reports and fees that were required to be submitted to the Office of the Secretary of State were never turned in, which caused the organization's registration status to be non-compliant. </p><p>DMV Futures, Inc. misrepresented its charitable impact so its officers could make money off generous Marylanders who just wanted to help young people get a job or pay for school, said Attorney General Brown. We are proud to work with the Office of the Secretary of State to stop these dubious charities and ensure that Marylanders generosity benefits legitimate organizations, not those who abuse the publics trust.</p><p>Charitable organizations and nonprofits assist Marylanders every day, and we will always zealously enforce the law in order to protect the public and the good work of legitimate nonprofits and charitable organizations, said Secretary of State Lee.</p><p>Officials say the solicitation occurred across Maryland, Virginia and Washington, D.C.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firefighters on the scene of two-alarm fire at vacant Old New Era Academy</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/firefighters-on-the-scene-of-two-alarm-fire-at-vacant-old-new-era-academy</link>
      <description>Fire crews with the Baltimore City Fire Department are on the scene of a two-alarm fire at Old New Era Academy.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 20:22:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Dominick Philippe-Auguste</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/firefighters-on-the-scene-of-two-alarm-fire-at-vacant-old-new-era-academy</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/firefighters-on-the-scene-of-two-alarm-fire-at-vacant-old-new-era-academy">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The Baltimore City Fire Department is on the scene of a two-alarm fire at a vacant school.</p><p>Officials say crews are on the scene of Old New Era Academy. </p><p>Heavy fire was show at temporary outdoor classroom trailers located at the rear of the main building. </p><p>No injuries have been reported at this time. </p><p><b>*This is a developing story and will be updated when more information becomes available.*</b></p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Howard County cities rank high on a national best places to live list</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/howard-county-cities-rank-high-on-a-national-best-places-to-live-list</link>
      <description>Ellicott City and Columbia have been named among the top five best places to live in Maryland, according to a new national ranking.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 19:28:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Siobhan Garrett</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/howard-county-cities-rank-high-on-a-national-best-places-to-live-list</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/howard-county-cities-rank-high-on-a-national-best-places-to-live-list">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Ellicott City and Columbia have been named among the top five best places to live in Maryland, according to a new national ranking.</p><p>Ellicott City ranks 13th nationally on the U.S. News and World Report's 250 Best Places to Live list for 2025-2026.</p><p>"Whether perusing the shops on Historic Main Street or enjoying a delicious meal on Route 40 or enjoying nature at one of the picturesque parks, there is no shortage of things to do in Ellicott City, said County Executive Calvin Ball, in a statement.</p><p>Columbia is ranked as the 4th best place to live in Maryland and 117th on the overall list.</p><p>Both cities got high marks for having a lower unemployment rate than the national average.</p><p>Other cities in Maryland that made the list are Bethesda, Rockville, Towson, and Bowie.</p><p>The best place to live in the U.S. according to this list is Johns Creek, Georgia</p><p>This year, U.S. News and World Report evaluated more than 850 cities nationwide to determine the rankings. </p><p>The rankings are based on a formula that factors in five indexes: quality of life, value, desirability, job market and net migration.</p><p>You can check out the entire list <a href="https://realestate.usnews.com/places/rankings/best-places-to-live?sort=match&amp;high_to_low=true">here</a>.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most DEI related books pulled from Naval Academy Library have been returned</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/most-dei-related-books-pulled-from-naval-academy-library-have-been-returned</link>
      <description>Most of the 381 DEI related books pulled last month from the U.S. Naval Academy library are reportedly going back on shelves.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 19:04:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Dickstein</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/most-dei-related-books-pulled-from-naval-academy-library-have-been-returned</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/most-dei-related-books-pulled-from-naval-academy-library-have-been-returned">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Most of the 381 DEI related books pulled last month from the U.S. Naval Academy library are reportedly going back on shelves.</p><p>This latest development was first reported by the Associated Press, citing anonymous U.S. Defense officials.</p><p>The Pentagon ordered the books in question to undergo a review ensuring they don't promote "divisive concepts and gender ideology for which the Trump Administration considers counteractive to its core mission.</p><p><a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/infocus/see-the-full-list-of-381-dei-related-books-pulled-from-the-u-s-naval-academy-library">A list of the books originally pulled</a> ranged in topics dealing with racism in America, White supremacy, and gender identity.</p><p>According to the Associated Press, the initial review directive were overly vague, resulting in a special committee to be formed.</p><p>The committee is tasked with determining what books are ultimately removed.</p><p>Per the Associated Press, the committee was given a more detailed criteria of what books should be eliminated.</p><p>That criteria is said to include key words like affirmative action, anti-racism, critical race theory, discrimination, diversity, gender dysphoria, gender identity and transition, transgender and white privilege.</p><p>The Navy on Wednesday could not confirm which books were returned.</p><p>But they did provide a statement to the Associated Press&nbsp;saying all materials identified and sequestered, for compliance.</p>The Associated Press contributed to this reporting.    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Senate passes resolution to end ban on the sale of gas-powered cars in Maryland</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/senate-passes-resolution-to-end-ban-on-the-sale-of-gas-powered-cars-in-maryland</link>
      <description>The United States Senate passed a resolution that will end the coming ban on the sale of gas-powered cars in several states including Maryland.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 19:03:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Rushaad Hayward</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/senate-passes-resolution-to-end-ban-on-the-sale-of-gas-powered-cars-in-maryland</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/senate-passes-resolution-to-end-ban-on-the-sale-of-gas-powered-cars-in-maryland">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The United States Senate passed a resolution that will end the coming ban on the sale of gas-powered cars in several states, including Maryland. </p><p>The resolution, known as Senate Joint Resolution 45, was applauded by Maryland State House Republicans as it will disapprove the California waiver to the Clean Air Act for Advanced Clean Cars II.</p><p>Governor Wes Moore adopted the California Advanced Clean Cars II (ACC II) and the Advanced Clean Trucks (ACT) rules in 2023.</p><p>This would've required all new passenger cars, trucks, and SUVs in Maryland to be zero-emission, by 2035. </p><p>In April, Governor Moore issued an Executive Order that delayed Marylands enforcement of these standards for two years.</p><p>Californias emission standards do not reflect the needs or values of Marylanders, said House Minority Whip Jesse Pippy. It is time to extract our state from this mess. Governor Moore needs to take action.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
