<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Local Eats</title>
    <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats</link>
    <description>Local Eats</description>
    <copyright>Copyright Scripps Media, Inc. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 19:17:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats.rss" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" />
    <item>
      <title>Southern Charm comes to Maryland: Zaxbys to open four restaurants across Baltimore Metro area</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/southern-charm-comes-to-maryland-zaxbys-to-open-four-restaurants-across-baltimore-howard-counties</link>
      <description>An agreement with the locally based Lattakia Group LLC, to develop four new locations, across the Baltimore Metro region.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 19:17:17 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Dickstein</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/southern-charm-comes-to-maryland-zaxbys-to-open-four-restaurants-across-baltimore-howard-counties</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/southern-charm-comes-to-maryland-zaxbys-to-open-four-restaurants-across-baltimore-howard-counties">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Zaxbys, out of Georgia, is the latest popular fast-food chain expanding into Maryland.</p><p>On Wednesday Zaxbys announced an agreement with the locally based Lattakia Group to develop four new locations, across the Baltimore Metro region.</p><p>"Were excited to introduce this beloved concept to our hometown in the coming years and to help create a dining experience that brings people together while contributing to local growth," said Lattakia. </p><p>Areas like Nottingham, Rosedale, Glen Burnie, and Ellicott City are currently under consideration.</p><p>Baltimore offers an incredible opportunity for us, and were thrilled to partner with the Lattakia Group, a dedicated and experienced local team, said Mike Mettler, Chief Development Officer of Zaxbys. "This marks the beginning of our presence in Baltimore and nearby communities.</p><p><a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/zaxbys-becomes-latest-popular-chicken-franchise-expanding-into-maryland">Last October WMAR-2 News reported</a> three Zaxbys restaurants opening along Maryland's Eastern Shore.</p><p>The first franchise location will be in Cambridge occupying an old Wendy's.</p><p>Although no official opening date's been announced, doors are expected to open by the end of 2025.</p><p>Two more spots in Easton and Berlin are expected to follow with potential for a fourth in Salisbury.</p><p>Zaxbys is known for its Chicken Fingers, wings and signature sauces.</p><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/a9/ce/8371244a4bd9a0222595344619e9/10-chicken-fingers-sauce-variety-2-1-23-0322-2.jpg"></figure>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hummus Republic coming to Owings Mills</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/hummus-republic-coming-to-owings-mills</link>
      <description>It's the first location in Maryland, and hopefully not the last. Hummus Republic is set to open in Owings Mills</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 14:47:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Kelly Groft</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/hummus-republic-coming-to-owings-mills</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/hummus-republic-coming-to-owings-mills">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>&nbsp;A little Mediterranean flair is coming to Owings Mills.</p><p>Hummus Republic is set to open its first Maryland location in Owings Mills on Saturday, May 17th.</p><p>It will be located at the Owings Mills Square Shopping Center.</p><p>If you show up from 11am- 1pm on opening day, you'll get a chance to try out some free samples, enjoy music, and get a chance to win other prizes.</p><p>You can check them out on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/people/Hummus-Republic-Maryland/61575120597804/">Facebook</a> for more.&nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/4b/89/cee1c19d4868a5fb71da51ff3409/hr-image.jpg"></figure>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tim Hortons, Canadian coffee-bakery chain, planning 10 new locations in Carroll, Howard Counties</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/tim-hortons-canadian-coffee-bakery-chain-planning-10-new-locations-in-carroll-howard-counties</link>
      <description>Many Marylanders have a must have coffee shop or drive-thru spot already mapped out as part of their daily routine.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:10:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Dickstein</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/tim-hortons-canadian-coffee-bakery-chain-planning-10-new-locations-in-carroll-howard-counties</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/tim-hortons-canadian-coffee-bakery-chain-planning-10-new-locations-in-carroll-howard-counties">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>We all need that morning pick-me-up, especially those of us with an early commute.</p><p>Many Marylanders already have their routine go-to coffee shop or drive-thru spot mapped out.</p><p>If Tim Hortons has their way, we'll have another option to consider.</p><p>The international coffee-bakery chain wants to expand here in the Old Line State.</p><p>Recently Hyatt Commercial Real Estate began searching for sites in Carroll and Howard Counties, to open 10 new Tim Hortons locations.</p><p>Tim Hortons is part of Restaurant Brands International Inc, which also owns the Burger King, Popeyes and Fire House Subs name brands.</p><p>Founded in 1964 by the late Canadian pro hockey player, Tim Hortons operates more than 5,500 restaurants in 13 countries</p><p>The chain's especially known for their selection of cold and hot coffee beverages, along with baked goods like its signature bite sized donut holes, called Timbits.</p><p>So far no specific locations or estimated opening dates have been revealed.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Owner of Puerto 511 in Mount Vernon to open second restaurant in Fells Point</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/owner-of-puerto-511-in-mount-vernon-to-open-second-restaurant-in-fells-point</link>
      <description>The fast-casual/sit-down Peruvian style restaurant, is the latest creation of chef Jose Victorio Alarcon, the owner of Puerto 511 in Mount Vernon.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 19:24:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Dickstein</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/owner-of-puerto-511-in-mount-vernon-to-open-second-restaurant-in-fells-point</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/owner-of-puerto-511-in-mount-vernon-to-open-second-restaurant-in-fells-point">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Fells Point visitors will soon have another dining option.</p><p>Empa 511 is coming to Browns Wharf in the 1600 block of Thames Street.</p><p>The fast-casual/sit-down Peruvian style restaurant, is the latest creation of chef Jose Victorio Alarcon, the owner of Puerto 511 in Mount Vernon.</p><p>Alarcon just signed the lease with Continental Realty Corporation.</p> <p>Brown's Wharf is made up of 1800s era brick and stone buildings along Baltimore's waterfront.</p><p>CFG Bank and Johns Hopkins rent space there as well, with Kilwins Chocolates and Ice Cream, Ten Thousand Villages, 7-Eleven, and Fells Point Surf Co. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Food hall opening soon in long-neglected part of West Baltimore</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/food-hall-opening-soon-in-long-neglected-part-of-west-baltimore</link>
      <description>It's part of a larger, years-long effort to revitalize the West North Avenue corridor. People who live here are excited about it finally coming to life.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 20:38:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Elizabeth Worthington</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/food-hall-opening-soon-in-long-neglected-part-of-west-baltimore</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/food-hall-opening-soon-in-long-neglected-part-of-west-baltimore">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>When you think of West Baltimore, or West North Avenue specifically, images like this might come to mind. </p><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/b5/06/01dc29294622afe7f37a7bf7de32/screenshot-2025-04-09-at-4-26-42-pm.png"></figure><p>"It is one of our most disinvested areas in the city. It is certainly very much in need," said Gary Rodwell, CEO of Coppin Heights Community Development Corporation.</p><p>These are the images they want you to associate with West North Avenue instead: neighbors gathering over good food and drink, brand-new apartments rising from former vacant lots, or a born-and-raised West Baltimorean investing in her own community by opening a new business.</p><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/4b/c0/161e9d5b49f2b544f2bf5c0d1748/screenshot-2025-04-09-at-4-16-21-pm.png"></figure><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/de/5c/60ed7ff641eabd1eecffbdc9e338/screenshot-2025-04-09-at-4-16-08-pm.png"></figure><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/65/18/d30a8a864d5c9cd7728f8afbbb1d/screenshot-2025-04-09-at-4-16-34-pm.png"></figure><p>"It was a food desert," said Debbie Wilson, owner of D&amp;B Deli. "And we wanted to figure out how we can impact the community. We wanted to bring a healthy food concept - well, as healthy as can be - healthy yet delicious."</p><p>"This area hasn't had a new food concept in 40 years," her sister and co-owner of the restaurant, Bianca Tabbs, told WMAR-2 News. </p><p>Their deli is part of The Mill On North Food Hall. It's home to seven local vendors in a building that was once a lumber mill, but hasn't seen any action in close to 20 years. The proud new owners are Neighborhood Housing Services of Baltimore and the Coppin Heights Community Development Corporation.</p><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/75/f6/9e4aa3914ce78ae5b79667245396/screenshot-2025-04-09-at-4-16-58-pm.png"></figure><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/75/a7/70b666c74b97b7d34ced99a9d86e/screenshot-2025-04-09-at-4-16-44-pm.png"></figure><p>"It's important to bring assets and amenities to communities that have often been left out of those opportunities," said Dan Ellis, CEO of Neighborhood Housing Services of Baltimore. "Bringing something that's really exciting, that's really cool to West Baltimore, to West North Avenue is something that makes people want to be here."</p><p>"My relatives used to live on this block and it was a time when there was community and memories and families," Gary Rodwell, CEO of Coppin Heights Community Development Corporation, told WMAR-2 News. "Now we're all excited about that returning as a result of the work that we are collectively doing."</p><p>That work includes includes <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/economic-authority-looking-for-qualified-developers-to-fill-west-baltimore-vacancies?fbclid=IwY2xjawJjtBhleHRuA2FlbQIxMQABHkL32wmLaSAzm0c89XaZ_t9NHCO3GVJaJIkWlUNGaCNgQAtkEaMS1wvvRqLd_aem_DJPyyv8rL4dl1BU0QxiYtA">new housing and mixed-use development along West North Avenue</a>. It's part of a larger effort to revitalize the neighborhood - an effort that dates back years. This particular project started in 2020.</p>  <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/f5/e1/be70507c4fc88ba642cbd29c4786/blue.jpg">  New food hall coming to West Baltimore    Food hall opening soon in long-neglected part of West Baltimore <p>"Because COVID happened, so everything was pushed back from materials to permits to health," Tabbs explained. "That process was interesting. But we learned a lot. We learned how to navigate."</p><p>People who live here are excited about it finally coming to life.</p><p>"Change is contagious," Wilson said. "This is an anomaly right now, but in a few years this could be normalized, and that's what we want to find a new normal, a new beginning, a new chapter."</p><p>The grand opening of The Mill On North is Thursday, April 24 at 10 a.m., but it's "softly" opened every day from 11 a.m. to 7 p.m. already. You can find more information <a href="https://themillonnorth.com">here</a>.</p><figure> <img src="https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/87/fe/7270dbde4266ac98bc760ec1f151/screenshot-2025-04-09-at-4-17-17-pm.png"></figure>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Original Beach Bar,' Sunset Cove permanently closes according to its facebook page</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/original-beach-bar-sunset-cove-permanently-closes-according-to-its-facebook-page</link>
      <description>This bar/restaurant, owned by Dave and Scott Steele, has been a staple in Middle River for over a decade.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 02:18:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Travis Case</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/original-beach-bar-sunset-cove-permanently-closes-according-to-its-facebook-page</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/original-beach-bar-sunset-cove-permanently-closes-according-to-its-facebook-page">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Sunset Cove, the beloved dockside oasis aka Middle River's original Beach Bar, is permanently closed according to its Facebook page.</p><p>This bar/restaurant, owned by Dave and Scott Steele, has been a staple in Middle River for over a decade.</p><p>The Cove was known for its relaxing atmosphere, variety of beverages, and great food.</p><p>It held a number of different themed events over the years, including game day Sundays, 4th of July celebrations, and even early spooky Halloween parties in the summer.</p><p>The Facebook post didn't give any reason for the shutdown but thanked their team and loyal customers.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Beanery to open in Owings Mills</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/coffee-beanery-to-open-in-owings-mills</link>
      <description>A new coffee shop will soon replace a Starbucks that closed in Owings Mills.&#xD;
&#xD;
Coffee Beanery is set to open April 7 at the New Town Village Shopping center,</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 21:13:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/coffee-beanery-to-open-in-owings-mills</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/coffee-beanery-to-open-in-owings-mills">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>A new coffee shop will soon replace a Starbucks that closed in Owings Mills.</p><p>Coffee Beanery is set to open April 7 at the New Town Village Shopping center, 9764 Groffs Mill Drive. </p><p>The <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/starbucks-moves-from-new-town-to-mill-station-in-owings-mills">Starbucks there closed in 2023</a>. </p><p>Coffee Beanery is a <a href="https://www.coffeebeanery.com/pages/our-story">Michigan-based company that dates to the 1970</a>s, with more than 100 stores nationwide, and 20 internationally. </p><p>A grand opening weekend is planned for April 18 through 20, with a mystery gift card giveaway, free cookie for the first 100 customers, games and prizes, and giveaways. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can you guess Yelp's top rated seafood restaurant in Maryland?</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/can-you-guess-yelps-top-rated-seafood-restaurant-in-maryland</link>
      <description>Maryland is known as a crab haven, but we offer all kinds of seafood. Everyone has their favorite local spots for steamed crabs or crab cakes.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 16:09:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Dickstein</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/can-you-guess-yelps-top-rated-seafood-restaurant-in-maryland</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/can-you-guess-yelps-top-rated-seafood-restaurant-in-maryland">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Maryland is known as a crab haven, but we offer all kinds of seafood.</p><p>Everyone has their favorite local spots for steamed crabs or crab cakes.</p><p>But only one was named best in the state, according to Yelp.</p><p>Drum roll please...</p><p>Yelp's top seafood restaurant in Maryland is...</p><p><a href="https://www.yelp.com/article/best-seafood-every-state">Thames Street Oyster House</a> in Fells Point.</p><p>"East Coast classics dominate the seafood menu at this waterfront spot in historic Fells Point, starting with the New England Lobster Roll (served warmed and buttered) with massive chunks of juicy lobster meat," is how Yelp describes this oyster house. "Other Yelper faves include the Baltimore Crab Cake, bursting with flavor and packed with [blue] crab meat and the North Atlantic Monkfish with potato gnocchi, touted for both taste and amazing texture.</p><p><b>SEE ALSO:</b> <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/a-columbia-food-truck-is-marylands-sole-representative-on-yelps-2025-list-of-top-100-places-to-eat">A Columbia food truck is Maryland's sole representative on Yelp's 2025 list of 'Top 100 Places to Eat'</a></p><p>It should be noted Thames Street Oyster House also finished #39 on Yelp's top 100 seafood spots of 2024.</p><p>By the way, <a href="https://broadwaymarketbaltimore.com/vendors/sal-sons-seafood/">Sal &amp; Sons Seafood</a> based out of Baltimore's Broadway Market made that list as well.</p><p>What say you, let us know your favorite Maryland seafood spot.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local restaurant reopening in new location after Key Bridge collapse</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/local-restaurant-reopening-in-new-location-after-key-bridge-collapse</link>
      <description>Owls Corner Cafe, a local Puerto Rican cafe, was originally in Dundalk located on North Point Boulevard right near I-695. After the Key Bridge collapsed, business was never the same.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 22:17:17 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ja Nai Wright</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/local-restaurant-reopening-in-new-location-after-key-bridge-collapse</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/local-restaurant-reopening-in-new-location-after-key-bridge-collapse">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Owls Corner Cafe, a local Puerto Rican cafe, was originally in Dundalk located on North Point Boulevard right near I-695.</p><p>After the Key Bridge collapsed business was never the same.</p><p>It impacted my business very closely because I had the wife of one of the guys that passed away at the bridge working with me," says Lilly Ordoez.</p><p>Ordoez says not only was it painful to hear the news of Jos Mynor Lpezs passing alongside the other five men, it was also hard for a lot of her customers to stop by since the bridge is gone.</p><p>We lost a lot of customers because their commute was very difficult for them. You know having to drive instead of 20 minutes having to drive an hour to get to this place to eat a quick lunch to go back to work its not doable," says Ordoez.</p><p>She says that loss of traffic turned into a huge loss in revenue.</p><p>I was only selling $50 a day, $100 a day you know, and I had three employees, and I have myself and the bills," she says.</p><p>So Ordoez and her husband closed the Dundalk location for good, but in December they were given a chance to open again, this time in Baltimore City.</p><p>Ordoez says at first her heart was broken having to close a cafe she says was her baby, but she is excited for the new cafe to open its doors on 842 North Calvert Street.</p><p>It feels amazing, it feels unreal, but I also know that it was meant to be," says Ordoez.</p><p>She says her biggest takeaway from the entire experience is resiliency.</p><p>Im glad to know that a year later you know people are not losing hope and they continue building back their lives so thats the attitude and Im grateful for that too," says Ordoez.</p><p>The new Owls Corner Cafe is set to open in April.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applebee's no longer coming to Owings Mills shopping center</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/applebees-no-longer-coming-to-owings-mills-shopping-center</link>
      <description>Applebee's has apparently pulled out of its plans to open in Owings Mills, at the Mill Station shopping center.&#xD;
&#xD;
The restaurant was originally shown on the shopping center's directory</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:36:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/applebees-no-longer-coming-to-owings-mills-shopping-center</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/applebees-no-longer-coming-to-owings-mills-shopping-center">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Applebee's has apparently pulled out of its plans to open in Owings Mills, at the Mill Station shopping center.</p><p>The restaurant was <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/applebees-coming-to-mill-station-in-owings-mills">originally shown on the shopping center's directory</a> in 2023, next to the AMC movie theater.</p><p>But now that space is listed as vacant. </p><p>Applebee's did not respond to previous requests for comment about when it might open there. </p><p>Applebee's has nearby locations in Westminster, Towson, and northwest Baltimore. </p><p><b>RELATED |</b> <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/tikka-shack-the-big-greek-cafe-opening-balt-county-locations">Tikka Shack, The Big Greek Cafe opening Balt. County locations</a></p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn how to get free food for a year at this Elkton Wendy's</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/learn-how-to-get-free-food-for-a-year-at-this-elkton-wendys</link>
      <description>That day at 10:30am, the first 100 customers in line to buy something will get a VIP voucher for a year's worth of free food.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:28:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Dickstein</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/learn-how-to-get-free-food-for-a-year-at-this-elkton-wendys</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/learn-how-to-get-free-food-for-a-year-at-this-elkton-wendys">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Wendy's restaurants around the country are undergoing new remodeling.</p><p>One of them happens to be nearby in Elkton, at 881 E. Pulaski Highway.</p><p>On March 22 Flynn Restaurant Group, who owns this particular Wendy's, will celebrate their new look.</p><p>That day at 10:30am, the first 100 customers in line to buy something will get a VIP voucher for a year's worth of free food.</p><p>There's only a few things you need to know...</p><p>Customers have to be at least 16-years-old in order to get a ticket.</p><p>The coupon is valid once a week for an entire year at the E. Pulaski Highway location.</p><p>Free food options include one sandwich, salad, or breakfast item per each visit.</p><p>Flynn Restaurant Group recently remodeled another Wendy's in Annapolis, on <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/learn-how-to-get-free-food-for-a-year-at-this-annapolis-wendys">West Street</a>.</p><p>This latest location is expected to employ 45 people.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Royal Buffet opens in Reisterstown's former Bill Bateman's Bistro</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/royal-buffet-opens-in-reisterstowns-former-bill-batemans-bistro</link>
      <description>There's a new buffet in town, and its owner has some more big plans.&#xD;
&#xD;
Royal Buffet officially opened this past weekend in Reisterstown's Chartley Park Shopping Center</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 20:56:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/royal-buffet-opens-in-reisterstowns-former-bill-batemans-bistro</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/royal-buffet-opens-in-reisterstowns-former-bill-batemans-bistro">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>There's a new buffet in town, and its owner has some more big plans.</p><p>Royal Buffet officially opened this past weekend in Reisterstown's Chartley Park Shopping Center - in the former home of Bill Bateman's Bistro.</p><figure class="op-interactive"> <iframe width="658" height="658" src="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DGzYvlvskVH/embed"></iframe></figure><p>The seafood-oriented buffet is promoting Japanese and Chinese specialties, like hibachi and its "sushi, sashimi, tempura, and grilled specialties," as well as "endless Boba [bubble tea] drinks." </p><p>The owners formerly ran Tokyo Seafood Buffet, for over a decade at Security Square Mall.</p><p>Co-owner Kevin Zheng said they're now planning to take that concept over to Route 40 in Catonsville.</p><p>The Route 40 buffet is also set to be called "Tokyo Seafood," and is currently in the works next to the popular Iron Age Korean BBQ restaurant (near Nuwood Road). </p><p>Zheng said the Route 40 buffet will be double the size of the Reisterstown space, and will have more seafood, and items like live crabs and oysters.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dito's (formerly Banditos) closing in Fed Hill after 14 years</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/ditos-formerly-banditos-closing-in-fed-hill-after-14-years</link>
      <description>Banditos is closing its Federal Hill location (now known as "Ditos") this Sunday - and being replaced by GameOn Bar + Arcade.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 15:51:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/ditos-formerly-banditos-closing-in-fed-hill-after-14-years</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/ditos-formerly-banditos-closing-in-fed-hill-after-14-years">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Banditos is closing its Federal Hill location (now known as "Ditos") this Sunday - and being replaced by GameOn Bar + Arcade.</p><p><b>RELATED |</b> <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/gameon-bar-and-arcade-closing-federal-hill-location">GameOn bar and arcade closing Federal Hill location</a></p><p><a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/federal-hill-staple-mothers-grille-announces-its-closing-after-25-years-in-business">The site of the former Mother's Grille</a>, meanwhile, will become Liv's Tavern.</p><p><b>RELATED |</b> <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/federal-hill-community-reacts-to-mothers-bar-closing">Federal Hill community reacts to Mother's bar closing</a></p><p>The owners of Mother's are also behind Banditos (<a href="https://banditostnt.com/locations/">which has six other locations</a>), and Wayward Bar &amp; Kitchen in Fed Hill. </p><p>Banditos has been on South Charles Street for 14 years.</p><figure class="op-interactive"> <iframe width="658" height="658" src="https://www.instagram.com/p/DHFXwftsWDv/embed"></iframe></figure>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puerto Rican cafe moves from Dundalk to downtown</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/puerto-rican-cafe-moves-from-dundalk-to-downtown</link>
      <description>Owls Corner Cafe is bringing Puerto Rican - that is, "Boricua" - flair to Mt. Vernon, next door to the longtime Iggie's Pizza on North Calvert Street.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 18:53:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/puerto-rican-cafe-moves-from-dundalk-to-downtown</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/puerto-rican-cafe-moves-from-dundalk-to-downtown">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>A colorful cafe that serves up "creole Boricua" food is making the move from Dundalk's North Point Plaza flea market to central Baltimore.</p><p>Owls Corner Cafe is bringing Puerto Rican - that is, "Boricua" - flair to Mt. Vernon, next door to the longtime Iggie's Pizza on North Calvert Street.</p><p>The restaurant was especially personally affected by last year's Key Bridge collapse.</p><p>One of the workers lost her husband in the tragedy, prompting Owls Corner to close temporarily and <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/03/27/us/baltimore-key-bridge-collapse-victims/index.html">being featured by CNN for her support of </a><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/05/07/us/sixth-body-baltimore-bridge-collapse-recovered/index.html">Jos Mynor Lpez</a>. </p><figure class="op-interactive"> <iframe width="658" height="658" src="https://www.instagram.com/p/C4_cFjYv79l/embed"></iframe></figure><p>Owls Corner is hoping to open in early April, at 824 North Calvert, said owner Lilly Ordoez. </p><p>About the new location, she said: </p> We fell in love with the diversity of the neighborhood; we feel that our concept of business and community fit perfectly in this community; we are a small family business with a passion for customer service and we want to invite as many people as possible to get to know more of our culture thru our flavors.     </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towson U. searching for new tenant after Starbucks closes downtown</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/towson-u-searching-for-new-tenant-after-starbucks-closes-downtown</link>
      <description>Starbucks has closed its small cafe inside the "StartUP at the Armory" building in downtown Towson.&#xD;
&#xD;
That means Towson University is looking for a new tenant.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 21:11:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/towson-u-searching-for-new-tenant-after-starbucks-closes-downtown</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/towson-u-searching-for-new-tenant-after-starbucks-closes-downtown">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Starbucks has closed its small cafe inside the "StartUP at the Armory" building in downtown Towson.</p><p>That means Towson University, which owns the historic Armory building, is looking for a new tenant.</p><p>The coffee shop closed at the end of 2024, confirmed the university.</p><p>Starbucks also has a nearby location at York Road and Bosley Avenue. </p><p>Towson University <a href="https://www.towson.edu/news/2023/historic-armory-purchase.html">bought the former National Guard Armory property for $8.6 million in 2023</a>, after leasing it since 2019.</p><p>The building is at the corner of Washington and Chesapeake avenues. </p><p>The university has <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/towson-university-prepares-to-open-175-million-health-professions-building">substantially stepped up its presence in downtown Towson in recent years</a>. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dunkin' planning Loch Raven Boulevard location</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/dunkin-planning-loch-raven-boulevard-location</link>
      <description>A drive-thru Dunkin' is proposed for the Loch Raven Boulevard in Towson. &#xD;
&#xD;
It's planned for the Loch Ridge Shopping Center</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:34:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/dunkin-planning-loch-raven-boulevard-location</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/dunkin-planning-loch-raven-boulevard-location">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>A drive-thru Dunkin' is proposed for the Loch Raven Boulevard in Towson. </p><p>It's planned for the Loch Ridge Shopping Center, at the intersection of Loch Raven and Joan Avenue, according to the site plan.</p><p>The developer wants to build a "Dunkin' Carry-out and Drive-Thru Lane," with an entrance from Joan Avenue. </p><p>Baltimore County is set to<a href="https://www.baltimorecountymd.gov/departments/permits-approvals-and-inspections/events/development-review-committee-drc-loch-ridge"> review the request on March 18</a>.</p><p>There is another Dunkin' down the street, on Joppa Road near Pleasant Plains. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shake Shack coming to Pikesville</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/shake-shack-coming-to-pikesville</link>
      <description>Shake Shack is getting ready to shake up a prominent Pikesville shopping center. It's set to open in the Festival at Woodholme</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 16:54:41 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/shake-shack-coming-to-pikesville</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/shake-shack-coming-to-pikesville">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Shake Shack is getting ready to shake up Reisterstown Road in Baltimore County.</p><p>It's set to open in the Festival at Woodholme, in a large corner spot that most recently held Mod Pizza and Corner Bakery Cafe.</p><p>That's according to the site plan from its leasing company.</p><p><b>RELATED |</b> <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/shake-shack-looking-to-grow-in-baltimore-region">Shake Shack looking to grow in Baltimore region</a></p><p>Shake Shack was "<a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/shake-shack-looking-to-grow-in-baltimore-region">actively seeking new locations in Virginia &amp; Maryland</a>" last year.</p><p>The burger restaurant has locations currently in Towson, downtown Baltimore, Canton, and Columbia.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tikka Shack, The Big Greek Cafe opening Balt. County locations</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/tikka-shack-the-big-greek-cafe-opening-balt-county-locations</link>
      <description>Tikka Shack and The Big Greek Cafe are among the new chain restaurants setting up shop in the Baltimore area.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 18:41:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/tikka-shack-the-big-greek-cafe-opening-balt-county-locations</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/tikka-shack-the-big-greek-cafe-opening-balt-county-locations">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Tikka Shack and The Big Greek Cafe are among the new chain restaurants setting up shop in the Baltimore area.</p><p><a href="https://www.tikkashack.com/">Tikka Shack</a> offers "seriously good Indian food" in a "friendly, casual atmosphere," where customers can customize their own curry dish (and spice level), or get items like naan pizza, naan tacos, vegetarian bowls, and chicken wings. </p><p>It's opening soon in White Marsh (on Campbell Boulevard), and in Owings Mills (at the Mill Station shopping center, <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/r-r-taqueria-closes-in-owings-mills-reopens-in-howard-co">replacing R&amp;R Taqueria</a>). </p><p>Tikka Shack is based out of Texas and has 16 locations. </p><p><a href="https://www.biggreekcafe.com/">The Big Greek Cafe</a>, meanwhile, is a D.C.-area restaurant that launched in Silver Spring in 2009. It now has 10 locations. </p><p>(The location in Urbana, Frederick County, however, has been closed <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DFgHOQxS7pR/?utm_source=ig_web_copy_link&amp;igsh=MzRlODBiNWFlZA==">since a vehicle crashed into the building, injuring two people</a>.) </p><p>It recently opened in Cockeysville, on York Road just north of Padonia.</p><p>Now, it's set to open in Owings Mills, at the Boulevard shopping center next to Stevenson University.</p><p>The Big Greek Cafe offers a <a href="https://www.biggreekcafe.com/menu/#favorites">variety of Greek dishes</a>, and some creative sides like fried calamari and "Our Famous Big Greek French Fries." </p><figure class="op-interactive"> <iframe width="658" height="658" src="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCQeN-GRCV7/embed"></iframe></figure><p>The restaurant declined to comment on whether they might be opening more Maryland locations.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"You're here to sing, dance and enjoy company": No TVs at Galway Bay</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/youre-here-to-sing-dance-and-enjoy-company-no-tvs-at-galway-bay</link>
      <description>Get a taste of Ireland, without leaving the state capital! WMAR-2 News Kara Burnett checks out Galway Bay to see what they've got on the menu for Annapolis Restaurant Week.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 15:30:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Kara Burnett</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/youre-here-to-sing-dance-and-enjoy-company-no-tvs-at-galway-bay</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/youre-here-to-sing-dance-and-enjoy-company-no-tvs-at-galway-bay">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>"A lot of history here on Maryland Avenue," said Steve Hardison, Executive Chef&nbsp;of Galway Bay Irish Restaurant &amp; Whiskey Bar. </p><p>The pub opened in 1998, bringing Irish hospitality to Annapolis. </p><p>"We really bring a traditional pub feeling. In the bar areas we don't have TVs which is usual in Ireland. You're here to sing, dance and enjoy company," said Hardison.</p><p>Their menu is full of traditional Irish dishes. </p><p>"People are looking for home cooked traditional foods like our corn beef and cabbage, shepherd's pie and our corned beef reuben," said Hardison.</p><p>From classic favorites to some new items, Hardison says Annapolis Restaurant Week gives them time to be creative and give returning customers something fun to look forward to.</p><p>"When you walk in, you feel comfortable. The people you work with on a day-in day-out basis, they're always here. It's my home away from home," said Hardison.</p><p>They're restaurant week <a href="https://galwaybaymd.com/menus1/annapolis-restaurant-week">menu</a> features a Seafood Lasagna with shrimp, scallops and blue crab. There's also an Irish Onion Ale Soup, Fried Chicken and Gravy and more.</p><p>Click <a href="https://www.downtownannapolispartnership.org/annapolis-restaurant-week">here</a> to see all of the participating restaurants.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crimson Coward officially opens in Eldersburg</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/crimson-coward-officially-opens-in-eldersburg</link>
      <description>A new chicken spot in Carroll County. Crimson Coward has officially opened in the Liberty Exchange shopping center, off route 26 in Eldersburg.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 19:19:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Dickstein</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/crimson-coward-officially-opens-in-eldersburg</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/crimson-coward-officially-opens-in-eldersburg">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>A new chicken spot in Carroll County.</p><p>Crimson Coward has officially opened in the Liberty Exchange shopping center, off route 26 in Eldersburg.</p><p>Although based out of Los Angeles, Crimson Coward considers themselves a Nashville Hot Chicken restaurant cooking up fresh, made-to-order<b> </b>hand-breaded goodness, with homemade sides like mac-n-cheese.</p><p>It's the chain's fifth Maryland location. Others are located in <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/a-bit-of-nashvilles-hot-chicken-is-opening-in-columbia">Columbia</a>, <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/crimson-coward-nashville-hot-chicken-to-open-4-restaurants-in-baltimore-region">Owings Mills</a>, and <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/its-marylands-newest-nashville-hot-chicken-spot">Pasadena</a>.</p><p>Crimson Coward is also coming to the Eastern Shore in Berlin.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Annapolisâ€™ Living Room': 30 years of bold flavors and music at 49 West</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/annapolis-living-room-30-years-of-bold-flavors-and-music-at-49-west</link>
      <description>From Snowstorm to Milestone: 49 West, a cozy Annapolis cafe, celebrates 30 years of food, art and community</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 17:46:11 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Kara Burnett</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/annapolis-living-room-30-years-of-bold-flavors-and-music-at-49-west</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/annapolis-living-room-30-years-of-bold-flavors-and-music-at-49-west">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Its been a dream of my husband and me, said Sarah Cahalan, owner of 49 West Coffeehouse, Winebar &amp; Gallery.</p><p>After working at a caf in Chicago, Sarah and her husband dreamed of having a spot of their own. On December 27th, 1995, they opened the doors to 49 West in downtown Annapolis.</p><p>Little did we know, a big snowstorm came through. People didnt know who we were or that we were open, but we opened anyway and just invited anybody who noticed us, said Cahalan.</p><p>The caf is celebrating 30 years in business. Some locals consider it Annapolis' Living Room. </p><p>49 West features live music, art, and a variety of food. Their menu offers breakfast, lunch, and dinner options, including pastries and some Korean dishes.</p><p>Our locals are what helped us get through all our hard times. Theyre here daily and weekly. That includes all our musicians who play here. We have art shows, and almost seven nights a week, we have live music, said Cahalan.</p><p>On any given night, you can walk into their listening room to enjoy jazz, American roots, folk, indie, bluegrass, bossa nova, and classical music.</p><p>We have a lot of singer-songwriters and up-and-coming artists. We also have a songwriters open mic every second Thursday of the month, said Cahalan.</p><p>Its an intimate environment with dinner and a show. Some of the dishes at 49 West are inspired by Cahalans childhood, including Bulgogi, Bibimbap, and Sarahs All Day Bowl.</p><p>This is something I grew up eating when my parents werent home. My mom always had rice in the rice cooker, and wed fry up some eggs. It was just a nice meal to get us through between coming home from school and dinner time, said Cahalan.</p><p>49 West is one of 37 restaurants participating in <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/a-good-deal-and-even-better-meal-whats-on-the-menu-for-annapolis-restaurant-week">Annapolis Restaurant Week</a>. The caf is offering 2-course and 3-course breakfast, lunch, and dinner specials ranging from $14 to $30.</p><p>Click <a href="https://www.downtownannapolispartnership.org/annapolis-restaurant-week">here</a> to see all of the restaurants.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A good deal and even better meal, what's on the menu for Annapolis Restaurant Week</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/a-good-deal-and-even-better-meal-whats-on-the-menu-for-annapolis-restaurant-week</link>
      <description>Indulge your tastebuds during Annapolis Restaurant Week! Buddy's Crabs &amp; Ribs is serving up a few dishes for a sneak peek.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 13:02:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Kara Burnett</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/a-good-deal-and-even-better-meal-whats-on-the-menu-for-annapolis-restaurant-week</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/a-good-deal-and-even-better-meal-whats-on-the-menu-for-annapolis-restaurant-week">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>8 days, 37 restaurants. Annapolis Restaurant Week runs from February 22 to March 2.</p><p>There are brunch deals, three-course dinner options, and a slew of wine specials.</p><p>WMAR 2 News Kara Burnett checked out a few spots. Her first stop: Buddy's Crabs &amp; Ribs.</p><p>"Winter in Annapolis is not a busy time of year for a waterfront city. All the time I come across somebody who says I've been coming to Annapolis for all these years. I never knew this was here. It's a fantastic time to show people what we're about" said Rick Chambers, Manager at Buddy's Crabs &amp; Ribs.</p><p>Buddy's is a longtime staple in Downtown Annapolis.</p><p>"The restaurant has been here since 1988. It's family-owned and operated. I've been working for them for most of my adult life at this point. I started here as a college job and kind of stuck around. They treat me like family," said Chambers.</p><p>Some of their lunch specials include cream of crab soup, The Annapolitan (a fried or grilled chicken breast topped with Buddys crab dip), and their rib basket.</p><p>Click <a href="https://www.downtownannapolispartnership.org/annapolis-restaurant-week">here</a> to see all of the participating restaurants.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Mini bullet trains" to deliver food at new sushi restaurant</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/mini-bullet-trains-to-deliver-food-at-new-sushi-restaurant</link>
      <description>Now a new sushi restaurant planned for south Baltimore promises to bring food to your table super-fast by using "mini bullet trains."&#xD;
&#xD;
Shinkansen Sushi - that's Japanese for "Bullet-train Sushi"</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 20:23:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/mini-bullet-trains-to-deliver-food-at-new-sushi-restaurant</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/mini-bullet-trains-to-deliver-food-at-new-sushi-restaurant">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Japan's bullet trains can travel up to 200 miles an hour. That would take you from D.C. to New York in about 60 minutes. </p><p>Now a new sushi restaurant planned for south Baltimore promises to bring food to your table super-fast by using "mini bullet trains."</p><p>Shinkansen Sushi - that's Japanese for "Bullet-train Sushi" - is setting up shop in the Baltimore Peninsula development.</p><p>They're offering a new spin (so to speak) on the traditional revolving-sushi restaurant. The mini-bullet trains will instead "deliver sushi dishes directly to customers' tables via a conveyor belt system," said the Baltimore Peninsula in a press release.</p><p>The eatery will also feature Japanese decor and a wide selection of both sushi and Japanese beers, sake and soju, along with street-food-inspired appetizers like Karaage and skewers.</p><p>The restaurant's owner David Chen owns multiple other Maryland restaurants, including Akira Ramen and Izakaya, Izakaya 68 (in Hunt Valley) and the new BBQ restaurant Volcano in Owings Mills. </p><p><b>RELATED |</b><a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/restaurant-market-cycling-yoga-more-coming-to-historic-south-balt-building"> Hot pot restaurant to replace Olive Garden in Owings Mills</a></p><p>Shinkansen Sushi will be in the Rye House building.</p><p>Chen said in a press release: </p> My family has been a part of the Baltimore community for decades, so were thrilled to bring our newest concept to Baltimore Peninsula. Weve seen firsthand the incredible loyalty of Baltimore customers, and we're excited to offer them a fresh and innovative sushi experience unlike anything else in the area.<p>Customers at Shinkansen Sushi can order from a set menu, unlike in traditional revolving sushi restaurants. The restaurant will offer both dine-in and take-out options - and will use robot servers "for enhanced service," as has been done at Chen's other restaurants. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Columbia food truck is Maryland's sole representative on Yelp's 2025 list of 'Top 100 Places to Eat'</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/a-columbia-food-truck-is-marylands-sole-representative-on-yelps-2025-list-of-top-100-places-to-eat</link>
      <description>Yelp is out with its 2025 Top 100 Places to Eat list, and one place in Maryland made the cut. Although Yelp categorizes the list as a restaurant, DMV Taqueria is a mobile food truck.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 18:33:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Dickstein</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/a-columbia-food-truck-is-marylands-sole-representative-on-yelps-2025-list-of-top-100-places-to-eat</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/a-columbia-food-truck-is-marylands-sole-representative-on-yelps-2025-list-of-top-100-places-to-eat">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Yelp is out with its 2025 Top 100 Places to Eat list, and one place in Maryland made the cut.</p><p>Although Yelp categorizes the list as a restaurant, DMV Taqueria is a mobile food truck based out of Columbia.</p><p>Yelp ranked them number 30 on this year's list.</p><p>This tasty truck says they offer tacos, quesadillas, and empanadas using only local and natural ingredients.</p><p>On their website, DMV Taqueria says its goal is "to become a regionally recognized brand."</p><p>Well, looks like they made it! </p><p>"We are thrilled to announce that DMV Taqueria has made it onto Yelps Top 100 Best Restaurants in the US for 2025," DMV posted on Facebook Saturday night. "A huge thank you to our amazing team and our incredible customers. This wouldnt have been possible without your support and love for our food."</p><p>Check out their <a href="https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100075856811891">page</a> to see where the truck will be next.</p><p>Columbia seems to be the place for good grub this year, because Yelp also recently chose another restaurant there to be on its Top 100 Date Night meal destinations.</p><p>Royal Taj on Benson Drive came in at number 63 on that list.</p><p>Here's how Taj describes themselves.</p><p>"With a regal ambiance adorned with elegant dcor, patrons are transported to a realm of luxury and sophistication. From aromatic curries to tandoori specialties, each dish at Royal Taj is meticulously crafted using authentic spices and traditional cooking techniques, ensuring an unparalleled culinary journey for discerning palates. Impeccable service and attention to detail complement the rich flavors, making every visit a memorable gastronomic affair."</p><p>In 2024 three Maryland restaurants earned spots on Yelp's Top 100 list, including Ekiben, in Baltimore, which finished in the top 20.</p><p><b>MORE:</b> <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/three-maryland-restaurants-make-yelps-top-100-places-to-eat-list">Three Maryland restaurants make Yelp's 2024 Top 100 Places to Eat list</a></p><p>For the full 2025 list, click <a href="https://www.yelp.com/article/top-100-us-restaurants-2025">here</a>.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlas Restaurant Group to open Admiral's Cup in Annapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/atlas-restaurant-group-to-open-admirals-cup-in-annapolis</link>
      <description>Atlas Restaurant Group has announced it's opening a second location of The Admiral's Cup in Annapolis.&#xD;
&#xD;
The Admiral's Cup has been a Fell's Point staple since the 1980s</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 18:27:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/atlas-restaurant-group-to-open-admirals-cup-in-annapolis</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/atlas-restaurant-group-to-open-admirals-cup-in-annapolis">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Atlas Restaurant Group has announced it's opening a second location of The Admiral's Cup in Annapolis.</p><p>The Admiral's Cup has been a Fell's Point staple since the 1980s, in a historic corner building on the waterfront. This second location expands Atlas' portfolio in Annapolis. </p><p>The Admiral's Cup will open in the historic Stevens Hardware building on the City Dock and is set to open in summer 2025.</p><p>Atlas plans to open two other restaurants in Annapolis - Marmo and Armada - this summer, as well as running the Annapolis Waterfront Hotel event venue. </p><p><b>RELATED |</b> <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/atlas-restaurant-group-announces-2-annapolis-restaurants">Atlas Restaurant Group announces 2 Annapolis restaurants</a></p><p>Atlas <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/news/local-news/atlas-group-buys-historic-admirals-cup-bar-in-fells-point">bought The Admiral's Cup in 2020</a>. </p><p>The Annapolis location will take over the first and second floors of the building at 142 Dock Street, and is also set to open this summer.</p><p>Atlas founder and president Alex Smith said: </p> We believe The Admirals Cup will fit in perfectly with the surrounding bars in downtown Annapolis. With its waterfront location, live music, and vibrant energy, it will be a great addition to City Dock and a place where both locals and visitors can come together to enjoy great entertainment and food.    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buffalo Wild Wings is making its Baltimore City debut</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/buffalo-wild-wings-is-making-its-debut-in-baltimore-city</link>
      <description>B-Dubs introduced its GO concept in 2020, allowing guests the option to either dine-in, order takeout, or delivery, on a smaller scale.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 17:33:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Dickstein</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/buffalo-wild-wings-is-making-its-debut-in-baltimore-city</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/buffalo-wild-wings-is-making-its-debut-in-baltimore-city">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Buffalo Wild Wings GO is ascending on Baltimore.</p><p>On Wednesday the restaurant chain announced the opening of its newest location at 843 East Fort Avenue.</p><p>B-Dubs introduced its GO concept in 2020, offering guests the option to either dine-in, order delivery, or take-out  just on a smaller scale.</p><p>Another GO franchise debuted at Horseshoe Casino in December, marking just two BWW restaurants in the entire City.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bubbakoo's Burritos chain to open first Howard County location</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/bubbakoos-burritos-chain-to-open-first-howard-county-location</link>
      <description>Howard County will soon get its first taste of the fast-growing Bubbakoo's Burritos chain.&#xD;
&#xD;
The "Mexican fusion" restaurant announced it's getting ready to open at Old Frederick and Marriottsville</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 16:33:41 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/bubbakoos-burritos-chain-to-open-first-howard-county-location</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/bubbakoos-burritos-chain-to-open-first-howard-county-location">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Howard County will soon get its first taste of the fast-growing Bubbakoo's Burritos chain.</p><p>The "Mexican fusion" restaurant announced it's getting ready to open at the junction of Old Frederick and Marriottsville roads. </p><p>The restaurant is moving into a former Dunkin' Donuts location. </p><p>This is the last of the recent crop of Bubbakoo's locations in the Baltimore region that the chain announced. </p><p><b>RELATED |</b> <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/bubbakoos-burritos-to-open-in-towson">Bubbakoo's Burritos to open 5 new locations, including Towson</a></p><p>There are now several Bubbakoo's spots in Baltimore County, as well as locations in Carroll and Anne Arundel counties.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nation's only fast-casual restaurant dedicated to chicken salad comes to Westminster</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/nations-only-fast-casual-restaurant-dedicated-to-chicken-salad-comes-to-westminster</link>
      <description>Here in Maryland we have a lot of fast, casual type restaurants, many of which revolve around chicken. But none seem to focus solely on chicken salad.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 14:25:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Dickstein</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/nations-only-fast-casual-restaurant-dedicated-to-chicken-salad-comes-to-westminster</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/nations-only-fast-casual-restaurant-dedicated-to-chicken-salad-comes-to-westminster">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Here in Maryland we have a lot of fast, casual type restaurants, many of which revolve around chicken.</p><p>But none seem to focus solely on chicken salad.</p><p>That's about to change because an Auburn, Alabama couple is bringing their love of chicken salad to Westminster.</p><p>Chicken Salad Chick is opening February 11 at 255 Baltimore Boulevard.</p><p>Founders Stacy and Kevin Brown say they are the nation's only fast-casual restaurant offering this type of concept. </p><p>"What sets Chicken Salad Chick apart is the personal touch that infuses every aspect of our menu. The unique flavors you see are more than just namesthey represent real people who have touched Stacys life. Each named flavor is a tribute to these real-life Chicks, and through our menu, we celebrate their stories," says the wife and husband duo.</p><p>Read more <a href="https://www.chickensaladchick.com/about">here</a>.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sheetz, Raising Cane's looking to open in Dundalk area</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/sheetz-raising-canes-looking-to-open-in-dundalk-area</link>
      <description>Sheetz convenience store and Raising Cane's restaurant are looking to come to the Dundalk area. Sheetz is interested in building a gas station/convenience store on North Point Boulevard at Wise Avenue</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 18:49:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/sheetz-raising-canes-looking-to-open-in-dundalk-area</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/sheetz-raising-canes-looking-to-open-in-dundalk-area">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Sheetz convenience store and Raising Cane's restaurant are looking to come to the Dundalk area.</p><p>Sheetz is interested in building a gas station/convenience store on North Point Boulevard at Wise Avenue, catty-corner from Royal Farms.</p><p>The plan was reviewed by Baltimore County on Jan. 16, in a <a href="https://www.baltimorecountymd.gov/departments/administrative-hearings/events/zoning-hearings-4334-4436-north-point-boulevard-8902">zoning hearing to request a special exception</a> to allow the gas station component.</p><p>Nick Ruffner, Public Affairs Manager for Sheetz, said in a statement:</p> Sheetz can confirm its interest in locating a store at this site. However, it's too early in the process to provide further details. <p>Raising Cane's, meanwhile, is on track to open at the Eastpoint Center, anchored by Redner's on Eastern Avenue. </p><p>The fast-food restaurant plans to open in 2027. It will be in a new space that is right next to Eastern Avenue.</p><p>Both chains have been expanding their presence in the greater Baltimore area.</p><p>Raising Cane's <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/raising-canes-to-open-in-owings-mills-bel-air-next-summer">expects to open</a> in Owings Mills, Glen Burnie and Bel Air later this year. </p><p>Sheetz recently opened its first Baltimore County location, on White Marsh Boulevard.</p><p>It's also planning to <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/sheetz-to-open-in-anne-arundel-county">open in Linthicum</a> and in Bel Air.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Franchisee looks to open 3 more Qdoba restaurants in Baltimore</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/franchisee-looks-to-open-3-more-qdoba-restaurants-in-baltimore</link>
      <description>At least four new Qdoba locations are expected to open in the Baltimore area. Meanwhile, Qdoba announced recently that a local franchisee is actively looking to open three more restaurants</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 19:58:25 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/franchisee-looks-to-open-3-more-qdoba-restaurants-in-baltimore</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/franchisee-looks-to-open-3-more-qdoba-restaurants-in-baltimore">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>At least four new Qdoba locations are expected to open in the Baltimore area. </p><p>The first will <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/game-sports-bar-panda-express-qdoba-coming-to-cockeysville">be a site that's been in the works</a> for some time, at Cockeysville's Yorktowne Plaza, on York Road. </p><p>Meanwhile, Qdoba announced recently that a local franchisee is actively looking to open three more restaurants in the Baltimore area. </p><p>There have not been any development agreements signed for those restaurants yet.</p><p>It's part of dozens of new Qdoba locations that the Mexican restaurant company says are moving forward nationwide.</p><p>Jeremy Vitaro, Qdoba Chief Development Officer, said in a press release that the company's "growth has never been stronger...Were proud to partner with franchisees who share our vision for delivering bold flavors and quality dining experiences to communities nationwide, setting the stage for long-term success.</p><p>Qdoba has 23 locations in Maryland. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baltimore County Restaurant Week runs through Sunday</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/chilly-weather-but-the-stove-is-hot-dig-into-baltimore-county-restaurant-week</link>
      <description>The countyâ€™s winter restaurant week runs through Sunday. Over 45 restaurants are participating.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 15:17:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Kara Burnett</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/chilly-weather-but-the-stove-is-hot-dig-into-baltimore-county-restaurant-week</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/chilly-weather-but-the-stove-is-hot-dig-into-baltimore-county-restaurant-week">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>We have our seared scallops over our roasted corn polenta with our butternut squash. Braised short rib over mashed potatoes. Duck fat fried donuts with red wine maple syrup. Blackened rock fish tacos with avocado and aioli. The micro greens are micro cilantro, so you'll get that big burst of cilantro in there as well."</p><p>Thats just some of the dishes youll find on the restaurant week menu at Atlantic Food &amp; Spirits in Catonsville.</p><p>"As soon as we were posted on the site, people started calling. Hey, what's going on? I heard about your restaurant, but I haven't been there. So it was really good to see over the weekend and on Monday, new faces coming in, said Bobby Bassett, Chef and Partner with Atlantic Food &amp; Spirits.</p><p>We have this large community that comes together, and we start to see some of the same faces and we see the different families. We've only been open three years, but in three years, I've got to see kids that come work for us grow up, said Basset.</p><p>Basset adds that Baltimore County Restaurant Week helps to keep business flowing during Dry January and the post-holiday rush. Its also a great boost for the locally-owned business that opened in 2022.</p><p>I grew up in Lansdowne, right around the corner. I went to school at Western Tech, which is three miles from this restaurant, and that's where I did my culinary program. So for me, when I had the opportunity to come here and own a restaurant in Catonsville, I was like, wow, this is kind of full circle, bringing me back home, said Basset.</p><p>You can get a four course dinner for $45 and a three course lunch for $25. After you dine, comes the wine. The restaurant is connected to their wine and spirits store that's open 7 days a week. And yes, that includes Sunday! </p><p>The countys winter restaurant week runs through Sunday. Over 45 restaurants are participating.</p><p>For a full list of participating eateries, check out the <a href="https://baltimorecountyrestaurantweek.com/">website</a>.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ben &amp; Jerry's opens at Baltimore Peninsula</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/ben-jerrys-opens-at-baltimore-peninsula</link>
      <description>The latest eatery at the Baltimore Peninsula is now open - and it's pretty sweet. Ben &amp; Jerry's has unveiled its first Baltimore location</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 15:51:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/ben-jerrys-opens-at-baltimore-peninsula</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/ben-jerrys-opens-at-baltimore-peninsula">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The latest eatery at the Baltimore Peninsula is now open - and it's pretty sweet.</p><p>Ben &amp; Jerry's has unveiled its first Baltimore location. It will be open from noon to 9 p.m., at 2450 Rye Street. </p><p>The ice-cream company joins other recent openings, including <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/pinkys-home-and-she-brought-not-one-but-two-slutty-vegans-with-her">Slutty Vegan</a>.</p><p>Jason &amp; Jerry Bhuller at Ben &amp; Jerrys said in a press release:</p> Were thrilled to bring the joy of Ben &amp;amp; Jerrys to Baltimore Peninsula. Everyone deserves to experience the magic of our ice cream, and we couldnt be more excited to be opening Baltimores first franchised location in such a special community. We look forward to serving up scoops for our neighbors!<p>This will be the only Ben &amp; Jerry's site in the greater Baltimore region. Ben &amp; Jerry's used to have a shop in Annapolis, but that has since closed. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Eats: Kneads Bakeshop</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/local-eats-kneads-bakeshop</link>
      <description>Located in Harbor East, Kneads has everything a stomach could ask for from smooth matcha lattes, honey old bay wings to wild mushroom pizza.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Travis Case</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/local/local-eats-kneads-bakeshop</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/local/local-eats-kneads-bakeshop">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Kneads Bakeshop boasts a massive kitchen that bakes around 3,300 pounds of dough daily.</p><p>Click <a href="https://youtube.com/shorts/MbTvILsW3i4?feature=share">here</a> to see how our trip went!</p><p>The WMAR-2 News digital team explored the hard work and care that goes into the mixing and baking process before the bread reaches customer's tables.</p><p>Located in Harbor East, Kneads offers everything from smooth matcha lattes and honey Old Bay wings to wild mushroom pizzaan option for every foodie.</p><p>Learn more about Kneads <a href="https://www.kneadsbakeshop.com/">here.</a> </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE! Casino joins the list of Winter Restaurant Week events</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/live-casino-joins-the-list-of-winter-restaurant-week-events</link>
      <description>Grab a plate, it's restaurant week season - winter edition! From Baltimore to Howard County, thereâ€™s a host of specials to dig into this season.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:55:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Kara Burnett</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/live-casino-joins-the-list-of-winter-restaurant-week-events</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/live-casino-joins-the-list-of-winter-restaurant-week-events">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Grab a plate, it's restaurant week season - winter edition! From Baltimore to Howard County, theres a host of specials to dig into this season.</p><p>You can get discounts and deals at dozens of restaurants and new this year, Live! Casino at Arundel Mills is getting in on the restaurant week fun.</p><p>We have our rock fish with our corn and crab risotto, a personal favorite of mine, said Dorothy Marshall, Sr. Marketing Manager Food and Beverage at Live! Casino &amp; Hotel Maryland.</p><p>Available for dinner, they have special three course menus for $39 at David's, Sports &amp; Social and Luk Fu with $69 deals at The Prime Rib and Koho.</p><p>Get out of the house when its cold, damp and gloomy to being able to enjoy with friends and family, said Marshall.</p><p>EXPLORE MORE RESTAURANT WEEK EVENTS: </p><p><a href="https://www.downtownannapolispartnership.org/annapolis-restaurant-week">Annapolis</a></p><p>February 22 - March 2</p><p><a href="https://baltimorerestaurantweek.com/">Baltimore City</a></p><p>January 24 - February 2</p><p><a href="https://baltimorecountyrestaurantweek.com/">Baltimore County</a></p><p>January 17-26</p><p><a href="https://www.visitharford.com/restaurant-week/">Harford County</a></p><p>January 17-26</p><p><a href="https://www.visithowardcounty.com/howard-county-restaurant-weeks/">Howard County</a></p><p>January 20 - February 2</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Owners of White Marsh's KÅŒNÅŒKÅŒ to open new Jamaican restaurant in south Baltimore</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/owners-of-white-marshs-konoko-to-open-new-jamaican-restaurant-in-south-baltimore</link>
      <description>The owners of two popular local Jamaican restaurants will open a "Reggae Fusion" restaurant at Baltimore Peninsula next year.&#xD;
&#xD;
It will be called BlÃ¼ CÄ (pronounced "blue kay")</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:00:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/owners-of-white-marshs-konoko-to-open-new-jamaican-restaurant-in-south-baltimore</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/owners-of-white-marshs-konoko-to-open-new-jamaican-restaurant-in-south-baltimore">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The owners of two popular local Jamaican restaurants will open a "Reggae Fusion" restaurant at Baltimore Peninsula next year.</p><p>It will be called Bl C (pronounced "blue kay") and will be in the Rye House apartment building. It's expected to open in early 2026.</p><p>The owners are part of the One Love Restaurant Group, which <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/news/local-news/jamaican-restaurant-to-open-on-the-avenue-at-white-marsh-this-summer">recently opened the popular</a> KNK in White Marsh and runs the longtime Island Spice Grille &amp; Lounge in Edgewood, Harford County. </p><p>Bl C promises "small plates made to share packed with a blend of authentic Jamaican dishes and international cuisine," live music, and "an elegant design complemented by shades of blue, pops of color and unique textures," according to a press release from the Baltimore Peninsula development.</p><p>One Love Restaurant Groups Sandy Tucker said in the release: </p> We had a vision for what would ultimately become Bl C for quite some time now, but when we found the perfect space at Baltimore Peninsula, thats really when it came together. The restaurants waterfront setting will perfectly align with the island vibe and mouthwatering dishes well be serving.<p><b>RELATED |</b> <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/winter-restaurant-week-events-for-2025-begin-in-january">Winter Restaurant Week events for 2025 begin in January</a></p><p><b>RELATED |</b><a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/slutty-vegan-getting-closer-to-opening-our-biggest-restaurant-in-south-baltimore"> Slutty Vegan getting closer to opening "our biggest" restaurant, in South Baltimore</a></p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter Restaurant Week events for 2025 begin in January</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/winter-restaurant-week-events-for-2025-begin-in-january</link>
      <description>Maryland counties and cities are gearing up to entice diners to eat local with their 2025 Winter Restaurant Week promotions.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:03:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Megan Knight</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/winter-restaurant-week-events-for-2025-begin-in-january</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/winter-restaurant-week-events-for-2025-begin-in-january">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The temperatures have dropped, there's snow on the ground (at least at the time this article was written) and everyone wants to hunker down inside for the next few months.</p><p>Now is a great time to check out new, local restaurants in your area with the return of Winter Restaurant Week promotions in several counties and cities.</p><p>During these events, restaurants will offer special prix fixed menus, discounts and deals. </p><p>Click on the county or city to go to the website for a list of participating restaurants. And if there's one we missed, email us at storyideas@wmar.com.</p><p><a href="https://www.downtownannapolispartnership.org/annapolis-restaurant-week" target="_blank">Annapolis</a></p><p>February 22 - March 2</p><p><a href="https://baltimorerestaurantweek.com/" target="_blank">Baltimore City</a></p><p>January 24 - February 2</p><p><a href="https://baltimorecountyrestaurantweek.com/" target="_blank">Baltimore County</a></p><p>January 17-26</p><p><a href="https://www.visitharford.com/restaurant-week/" target="_blank">Harford County</a></p><p>January 17-26</p><p><a href="https://www.visithowardcounty.com/howard-county-restaurant-weeks/" target="_blank">Howard County</a></p><p>January 20 - February 2</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former founder/CEO of Potbelly to open more stores in Maryland</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/former-founder-ceo-of-potbelly-to-open-more-stores-in-maryland</link>
      <description>The man who founded and once ran Potbelly Sandwich Works is planning to open dozens more restaurants in this area - including six or so in greater Baltimore.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 22:04:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/former-founder-ceo-of-potbelly-to-open-more-stores-in-maryland</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/former-founder-ceo-of-potbelly-to-open-more-stores-in-maryland">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The man who founded and once ran Potbelly Sandwich Works is planning to open dozens more restaurants in this area - including six or so in greater Baltimore.</p><p>Bryant Keil, who grew Potbelly into a national chain starting in the mid-1990s, now wants to open at least 35 new restaurants in Maryland, Pennsylvania and Virginia, over the next eight years.</p><p>That includes at least 15 in Maryland.</p><figure class="op-interactive"> <iframe width="658" height="658" src="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-c7tetNfPs/embed"></iframe></figure><p>Keil and his son, Hampden, just opened the first Potbelly in Frederick, on Dec. 18. </p><p>He said the opening was "really incredible," with a record-breaking first week and second week, which "was pretty amazing." </p><p>They're also finalizing two or three leases in the Baltimore area, but he said he couldn't yet disclose the exact locations of any more stores.</p><p>There are several Potbelly restaurants currently in the area, including Towson, Glen Burnie, Mt. Vernon, Charles Village, and downtown - but Keil doesn't own those. </p><p>Potbelly has some franchised stores, and some corporate-owned ones.</p><p>Keil grew up in Montgomery County, and said his "primary goal is to add stores to the Potbelly system."</p><p>"We're really excited about it. Our stores are doing really well and it's nice to see customers loving the brand," he said. "The food is really good, and the people are really nice, and the stores aren't cookie-cutter, they're fun, and that makes a big difference to me."</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Papi's Tacos on Harford Road to become Alexander's Tavern</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/papis-tacos-on-harford-road-to-become-alexanders-tavern</link>
      <description>The popular Papi's Tacos chain will be transforming its northeast Baltimore location into a different concept: Alexander's Tavern.&#xD;
&#xD;
Charlie Gjerde owns both Papi's Tacos and Alexander's Tavern</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 16:07:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/papis-tacos-on-harford-road-to-become-alexanders-tavern</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/papis-tacos-on-harford-road-to-become-alexanders-tavern">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>The popular Papi's Tacos chain will be transforming its northeast Baltimore location into a different concept: Alexander's Tavern.</p><p>Charlie Gjerde owns both Papi's Tacos and Alexander's Tavern, which has been on Broadway in Fell's Point for years.</p><p>Papi's SoHa Union, in the Lauraville area, posted on social media:</p> Although Papis loved its time in this location we have made a decision that we feel is best for the company, our staff and the neighborhood. We are thrilled to announce a re-brand of Papis Tacos Soha Union as Alexander's Tavern Soha! We can't wait to share our flagship concept, which is near and dear to our hearts, with you all and have so much more in store for the community! We are so ready for a NEW BRAND and a NEW LOOK!<p>Papi's first opened its location in the SoHa Union building, on Harford Road at Southern, a year ago.</p><p>Alexander's Tavern <a href="https://www.alexanderstavern.com/main-menu">offers an assortment</a> of pizzas, sandwiches, burgers, salads, and traditional "tavern fare." </p><p>Papi's Tacos posted that this weekend will be its last time as Papi's. It will close for a few days starting Jan. 13 to make the rebrand.</p><p>The post said: "Although this location is changing, please dont forget our other Papis locations in Fells Point, Hampden, and Towson."</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Costs force Cocina Luchadoras to close Broadway restaurant in Fells Point</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/high-costs-force-cocina-luchadoras-to-close-main-fells-point-restaurant</link>
      <description>A small locally owned Mexican restaurant is shutting its doors, citing rising costs. Cocina Luchadoras on S. Broadway announced its closure on social media.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 15:02:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Ryan Dickstein</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/high-costs-force-cocina-luchadoras-to-close-main-fells-point-restaurant</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/high-costs-force-cocina-luchadoras-to-close-main-fells-point-restaurant">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>A small locally owned Mexican restaurant on S. Broadway is shutting its doors.</p><p>Cocina Luchadoras announced its closure on social media, citing rising costs.</p><p>It is with humble gratitude and a heavy heart that I announce the closing of our Upper Fells location of Cocina Luchadoras. This has been an incredibly difficult and emotional decision, and after 8 beautiful years, I am sad to say goodbye to a location that has given so much to the Upper Fells community," wrote owner Rosalyn Vera. "Regrettably, I could not manage the rising costs of operating the restaurant."</p><p>A few days after deciding to close, Vera posted an update stating the restaurant would soon operate out of Saunter Corner Bar in Upper Fells Point.</p><p>"Were excited to begin a new chapter! Starting Monday, January 6," Vera wrote. "Were so grateful to Saunter Corner Bar for helping us keep the Luchadoras spirit alive."</p><p>Vera said the new hours would be Monday through Friday, 11am to 3pm.</p><p>Saunter opened in September 2024 on E. Lombard Street. </p><p>They've been working to transform the bar into an arts space with plans to relaunch as <a href="https://www.meanderartbar.com">Meander Art Bar </a>on February 1.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chipotle expected to open new Parkville location</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/chipotle-expected-to-open-new-parkville-location</link>
      <description>Chipotle will be opening a second Parkville location.&#xD;
&#xD;
The Mexican fast-food chain is replacing the spot occupied by Mamma Lucia</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 20:52:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/chipotle-expected-to-open-new-parkville-location</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/chipotle-expected-to-open-new-parkville-location">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Chipotle will be opening a second Parkville location.</p><p>The Mexican fast-food chain is replacing the spot occupied by Mamma Lucia restaurant in the Perring Plaza shopping center on Joppa Road. </p><p>Mamma Lucia <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/mamma-lucia-closing-in-parkville-after-26-years">closed in November, after 26 years</a>. </p><p>Chipotle is now listed on the <a href="https://properties.federalrealty.com/property/perring-plaza/3314012">leasing map</a> for the shopping center. </p><p>Chipotle also has a location in the Parkville Shopping Center, on Harford Road near the city line. </p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlas Restaurant Group releases details on new Japanese restaurant in Baltimore</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/atlas-restaurant-group-releases-details-on-new-japanese-restaurant-in-baltimore</link>
      <description>Atlas Restaurant Group has release more details about its new Japanese restaurant set to open in the Harbor East/Fells Point area.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:20:15 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/atlas-restaurant-group-releases-details-on-new-japanese-restaurant-in-baltimore</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/atlas-restaurant-group-releases-details-on-new-japanese-restaurant-in-baltimore">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Atlas Restaurant Group has release more details about its new Japanese restaurant set to open in the Harbor East/Fells Point area.</p><p>It will be called Kannon, "a new Japanese izakaya and hand roll concept set to open in Baltimore in Spring 2025."</p><p><b>RELATED |</b> <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/atlas-group-to-open-japanese-restaurant-in-historic-fells-point-building">Atlas Group to open Japanese restaurant in historic Fells Point building</a></p><p>The company said: "Helmed by Atlas Concept Chef Timur Fazilov, known for his culinary excellence at Azumi in Baltimore and Houston, Kannon will feature a bold menu focused on handrolls, sashimi, nigiri, and crudo."</p><p>Atlas Group president Alex Smith said in a statement:</p> Kannon is a project close to my heart, inspired by my travels to Japan, Los Angeles, and New York. The goal is to bring a moderately-priced, neighborhood-driven, izakaya experience to Baltimore that celebrates the art of Japanese cuisine in a casual and lively atmosphere. I am excited to add Kannon to our citys growing culinary landscape.     </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sheetz to open in Anne Arundel County</title>
      <link>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/sheetz-to-open-in-anne-arundel-county</link>
      <description>Sheetz is getting ready to open its first Anne Arundel County location.&#xD;
&#xD;
It will be in the BWI area, at 1441 West Nursery Road in Linthicum.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 17:21:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bryna Zumer</author>
      <guid>https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/sheetz-to-open-in-anne-arundel-county</guid>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<html lang="en">    <head>        <meta charset="utf-8">        <meta property="op:markup_version" content="v1.0">                    <link rel="canonical" href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/sheetz-to-open-in-anne-arundel-county">                <meta property="fb:article_style" content="default">    </head>            <p>Sheetz is getting ready to open its first Anne Arundel County location.</p><p>It will be in the BWI area, at 1441 West Nursery Road in Linthicum. </p><p>The company has announced a hiring event for the store on Jan. 8, to be held in Linthicum Heights.</p><p>This would be the fourth Sheetz location along the general I-95 corridor in Maryland. </p><p>The first Baltimore County location <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/localeats/sheetz-announces-grand-opening-for-first-baltimore-county-store">just opened in White Marsh/Middle River</a>. Sheetz is also working on a store in Bel Air, which would be its second in Harford County.</p>    </html>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
